<book title="TechnodeFirmaCraft">
  <chapter id="index">
    <section>
      <p bold="true">TechnodeFirmaCraft</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p color="#CC3333">Table of contents</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <link ref="intro" color="#000066">-&gt;General Notes</link>
      <link ref="tips" color="#000066">-&gt; Tips and Tricks</link>
      <p space="10"/>
      <link ref="quest" color="#000066">-&gt; Benanov's Sarcastic Questbook</link>
      <p space="10"/>
      <link ref="storage" color="#000066">-&gt; TFC Storage</link>
      <p space="10"/>
      <link ref="progression" color="#000066">-&gt;Biletooth's Progression</link>
      <p space="10"/>
      <link ref="rockhounding" color="#000066">-&gt;Benanov and Rockhounding</link>
      <p space="10"/>
      <link ref="seedfinding" color="#000066">-&gt;Finding A Decent TFC Seed</link>
      <p space="10"/>
      <link ref="changelogs" color="#000066">-&gt;Pack Changelogs</link>
    </section>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id="intro">
    <section>
      <p bold="true">Introduction</p>
      <link ref="index" color="#CC3333">&lt;- Index</link>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Welcome to the latest release of TechnodeFirmaCraft for MC 1.12.2</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>A lot of work has got us to this point, but there is always work left to do. We always need your assistance to get us the polish and shine that TNFC was known for.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>TFC-NG or TNG has brought the vast majority of the TFC systems to 1.12.2. <link href="https://tng.terrafirmacraft.com/Differences_From_Classic">Some got left behind </link> but overall the mod is very slick and well put together.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>We've added some new mods, some familiar mods from 1.7.10 and mostly have them all working together to provide a long and interesting experience from Stone Age to the beyond.</p>

      <p>As it stands now:</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The set of mods are in place. The core oregen is in place. This means that worlds are stable as we update the other bits.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The other bits will be scripty stuff to integrate mods in, change recipes, change machine mechanics and config changes to balance things out.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>We can't promise a no-restart-ever future for TNFC but I believe it's pretty stable and you should be able to continue with a world along many TNFC updates.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The progression path is similar to 1.7.10 TNFC.</p>
      <p>The core initial gameplay is very much the TFC experience. You will need to progress with TFC to at least the Iron Age before the features and benefits (and rockets) in TNFC start to become feasible.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The BetterWithMods, Astikorcarts and HorsePower mods allow some early automation and are worth exploring. Once solidly into Iron, Immersive Engineering will open up. Most of it will be gated by steel, so it's wise to continue along the TFC progression (ideally all the way to coloured steels). Immersive Engineering and Petroleum will open up a lot of options.</p>
      <p>PneumaticCraft and Rockhounding open up all sorts of options. Leading finally to</p>
      <p>Advanced Rocketry! The moons and planets yield many things, including The End, which is a moon around another planet you'll have to find.</p>
      <p>So tech up, get to The End, kill the Dragon and craft the ultimate prize from it's Egg!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>We think we like the various settings and recipes, lot's of work has gone into balancing and setup.</p>
      <p>But this is where you come in. We need you to let us know about all the issues. Something exploitable, or impossible, or just excessively expensive?</p>
      <p>Need to know where we need to continue to polish things.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Also, the IE hemp seeds no longer come from zombies. Instead, if you want Hemp you gotta get high. If that's not enough of a clue, use a knife or a scythe on grass at heights greater than 170. It's a rare drop.</p>

      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The Issues link on the Main Page will take you to the Github repo for pack. Where we're going to corral and work the issues.</p>
      <p>Get your issues in. Suggestions, ideas, and requests are all good too.</p>


      <p>
        <link href="http://github.com/anodecathode/technodefirmacraft">Technodefirmacraft Github</link>
      </p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Good luck. 2837</p>

    </section>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id="tips">
    <section>
      <p bold="true">Tips</p>
      <link ref="index" color="#CC3333">&lt;- Index</link>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Things to be aware of in TechnodeFirmaCraft for MC 1.12.2</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You can now change the size of the rock layers. If in single player, I recommend setting Rock Layer size to 4 to increase the number of rock layers in your immediate area. Smaller than 4 results in very tiny rock layer regions.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The IE hemp seeds no longer come from zombies. Instead, if you want Hemp you gotta get high. If that's not enough of a clue, use a knife or a scythe on grass at heights greater than 170. It's a rare drop.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You can weld ingots! There's no weld button - shift-right-click on the anvil with hammer in hand</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Put straw in your inventory to stay warm.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Make a pink boat with an alternative recipe not requiring a saw.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Tough TFC grass can break stuff 2 blocks above it when growing.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Pave under anything you want to keep, otherwise grass will eat your pipes.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Crops and fruit trees are very particular about growing conditions.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Stay hydrated. Stay well fed.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Get high; Y > 170; and find Hemp seeds</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Want a questbook? Benanov made one just for you!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Buckets no longer are used for planters. Using one will destroy your planter.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Alternate paper making recipes exist...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Alternate sugar making recipes exist...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>There are hint rocks for the minerals that don't have surface ores...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Vein Info tab in JEI is key to knowing where to find ores...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Horsepower devices do not require a familiarized animal, but they might not stay!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You can use ice or snow blocks in your inventory to stay cool...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Being in the dark without a light source will lead to Gloom, Blindness or even the Grue! </p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The IE Excavator does not like to touch TFC blocks (including snow!) 2 block minimum!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Barrels of water or other liquid can be used in crafting recipes...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Placing a ladder on every second block works perfectly fine...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Space Suit and PneumaticCraft Armour are both immune from temperature...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The Nether is hot! Like really really hot!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Heat is a killer. Wear a hat...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Make Waystones using red gems and gold...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Spiders can drop redstone...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Creepers can drop glowstone...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Come see us on Reddit for sarcastic answers to your questions...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Don't eat the horse that powers your horse grindstone...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Do not for any reason stack two Raintanks on top of each other or TFC Barrels...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Don't ask me about Rockhounding, I'm as confused as you are...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Shift-click crafting stacks of stuff is super laggy... No idea</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The AR Lathe makes crafting pistons much easier...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The IE Metal Press makes your crafting life easier...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Horses require a halter to ride. Check JEI...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Use a stone shovel to remove items from RH Evaporation Tank...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The refrigerator takes power in from the back top. Then wait!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Coal Coke is correctly usable for Steel...in the IE Blast Furnace...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>HV IE Wires will give you a boost!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Bugs are free with every purchase...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The IE Revolver and Mining Drill have rendering issues sometimes...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Direwolves are not friendlier versions of TFC Wolves...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>RH Power stations can use RF and Fuel. Recipes need one/the other/both...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Sneak right-click full ingots to demold...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Powderkegs pack boom into one block with 100%% drops...Go find that sulfur</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>NC Alloy Furnace can be useful for those two part alloy recipes...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Blue flowers can be found in cool dry areas and hotter wet areas...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Mature dead crops yield the most seeds...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Pigvil sometimes shows up for metal carrots, but he needs to like you first...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Chisel needs a hammer in the off-hand...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Prospector's Pick scans 12 blocks in every direction...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Waystone travel uses kaolinite powder to power it...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The End is a moon of another planet...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The ultimate prize awaits, just need a Dragon's Egg...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You need at least a black steel pick to mine obsidian and go to the Nether...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Spawner fragments from the nether can construct your own mob spawner...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Make a leather forging bib and stop dying of heatstroke next to the forge...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Don't use /kill if you aren't comfortable editing your player data after. It's broken...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Shaders not working? Disable all THREE AR skyboxes! In config/advRocketry...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Increase your prospecting skill by clicking on ore separated more than 13 blocks apart!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Panning for gold and silver nuggets is a legitimate path to early bronze...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Hiking Boots let you move through grass without slowdown...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Few crops grow over 400 or under 100 rainfall...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Toxic Slimes don't like Raspberry or Blackberry Bushes...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Remove the attachment from a firepit with sneak right click, but not while it's hot...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Toxic Slimes will climb ladders to get to you...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Making a server? Set level-type=tfc_classic in server.properties</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Tree nuts are harvestable with the right equipment in season, but it's exhausting...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You should read the tips.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Make sure to unclaim or allow explosions before you waste the gunpowder!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>While PNC loves to put out flames, there are several ways to relight them...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Lassos are effective hunting and fishing accessories.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Don't make a pit kiln near peat blocks...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Dirt paths are NOT a solid block, and pit kilns will not work when bounded by them.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Aggregate acts more like vanilla gravel...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Default PNC Amadron deals can be very helpful...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Just go for the regular drone, the harvest drone isn't worth the headache.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Save that creosote, select PNC and RH systems can burn it.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>IE cloches are NOT a farm substitute until you have RF to burn.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>IE cloches need steady power to work.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Put a TFC seed into a cloche first before using it to grow anything else.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Bonemeal works as fertilizer in the IE cloche.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>BWM saw makes a very tasty pigman grinder.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Mushrooms respawn but do not spread in the Overworld...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Desperate to warm up when huddling in a winter corner? Put straw in your 2x2 grid!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Iron scrap correctly melts in the crucibles...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>What can some redstone, three hoppers, a water barrel, chests, and a crucible make?</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Cheesemaking is very different than described in the TFC book. See the firmalife wiki.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Breadmaking is very different than described in the TFC book. See the firmalife wiki.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Only one connected bread oven requires fuel while cooking bread...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Greenhouse parts are cheaper out of aluminum.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Dig down in the northwest corner of the southeast chunk of a nugget cluster.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>IE fluid pipes sometimes magically develop a gap, usually just a visual glitch.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Dilithium and Iridium are only available on *OTHER* celestial objects.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Latex collection requires a special fluid bowl on the mount...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The Observatory and Astrobody Data Processor only look for asteroids.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The Warp Controller can search for other planets.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Osmium and Tungsten Steel make the fastest tools.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>To figure out a new anvil recipe, use the communitive property of smithing, A+B = B+A!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>TNFC's many ores only leave hints within 30 blocks of the surface instead of 35!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Don't harvest animals for food until you need to, meat doesn't expire on the hoof!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Aged and smoked cheeses last a long time.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The ruins of ancient civilizations on other planets may reveal the Infernal Enchanter!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Signpost arrows can be rotated using left and right click with a signpost wrench.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Maximum HP is 1750. To get there, eat healthy! Drinking milk after meals can help.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Use the tab key to repeat the last crafting recipe.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Don't put a speed upgrade in the fluid filter slot of the Gasification Plant.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You can live in the roof section of your greenhouse.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>A flock of birds is the ultimate early game multiplayer food source.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>A fish tank is the ultimate mid-game multiplayer meat source. Feed with hemp seeds.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fish can be turned into tallow for candles.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>A crucible heats ores at least 40% faster than the forge.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Glowing mushrooms self-multiply and have the same light level as torches. Tacky.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Move around underwater in your nearest hot spring for fastest healing! Don't drown!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Plant fruit trees at least 5 blocks apart to get the most fruit.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Saplings of any kind will not grow if crowded.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Many vanilla signs close together may severely impact your FPS.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Any seed is a good seed, but a garlic seed is the best seed.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Witches can drop sugar!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Holding shift with the mining drill mines a single block.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The RH metal alloyer can make some cheap ingots!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Preheating iron ore before filling the blast furnace can save fuel.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Cobble slabs are a miner's delight.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Garlic bread is a good way to eat grains and vegetables.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You CAN fire pottery in a crucible! It's faster than the forge!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You CAN cook food in the crucible, but it won't taste all that great.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You can use rotten meat to make tallow - reduce, reuse, recycle!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Wooden firestarter works on charcoal pits... and on log piles, beware!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Some player actions may take a long time on a busy server.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Set rock layer size = 4 in world generation to decrease exploration needs.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Basil for pizza can be found in moderate climes with normal to wet rainfall.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The autorun key (R by default) may save your fingers on those long boat trips.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Crops and fruit trees are very particular about growing conditions. Rainfall and temp both apply to whether a crop or fruit tree will grow.</p>
      <p>This <link href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1Ghw3dCmVO5Gv0MMGBydUxox_nwLYmmcZkGSbbf0QSAE/edit#gid=37622487">spreadsheet</link> will provide all the details about crops and fruit trees and the conditions they require.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The IE Electric Lights and Electric Heater are great ways to automate heat in the winter</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The IE Excavator does not like to touch TFC blocks (including snow!). When you build the Excavator, remove all blocks within 2 of the Excavator's bucket wheel (including the sides). Also put a roof over the top (with a 2 space gap) to prevent snow from accumulating on the wheel. Failure to do so will crash your game or server.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>When you make a space station, make copies of the station id chip. If you for some reason lose your only chip and can't get back to the station with a space elevator, the station is lost</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>If you're having timeout issues connecting to a TNFC server, or sometimes even loading a save in single player.</p>
      <p>Add this parameter to the startup for the server:</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p bold = "true">-Dfml.readTimeout=512</p>
      <p>Or even to the java parameters for the client.</p>
    </section>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id="quest">
    <section>
      <p bold="true">Benanov's Sarcastic Questbook</p>
      <p space="10"/>
<p space="2"/>
      <link ref="index" color="#CC3333">&lt;- Index</link>      
      <p>You all wanted a quest book. This is not the quest book you deserve, but it's the quest book you need.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p bold="true">STONE AGE</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Find rocks and sticks.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: You can make stone tools. Get banging.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Cut some grass and look for plants near the water that can assist in the creation of a straw hat. Oddly enough, the reeds required only grow in colder climates.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: It looks silly, but it will keep you cooler.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Throw a log, three sticks down on the ground, and some straw, then light it</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: A fire. That and you can now tell Prometheus, "new phone who dis"</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: kill a cow, a horse, a dire wolf (hah), a bear, or other large animal for a Large Hide. Place atop two thatch blocks.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: a bed that sets your spawn point, so you don't have to run south from spawn every time you die.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Find some seeds.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Straight out of the late 90's, it's co-ed naked farming: grab a hoe and plant your seed.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Figure out which key is used to place objects on the ground so you can build your first pit kiln.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: it's V. The V key. Now make me a pretty pot. Dye it black, because we know you've been killing squid for food.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p bold="true">COPPER AGE</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Find some copper ore.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Copper Saw. Look, I know you all want to make a pick first...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Find some more copper ore.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Okay, NOW you can make a pick.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Even more copper ore.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: A storage problem. Easily solved by making chests. THIS time.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Find Basalt, Andesite, Rhyolite, or one of the other igneous rocks</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Stone Anvil.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>PRO TIP: Anything made with Basalt looks like ass.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Find Flux-bearing stone - Limestone, Dolomite, or Marble. Grind it. Make flux.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: You can weld ingots! There's no weld button - You shift-right-click on the anvil with a hammer in your hand to weld ingots together.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Flux + water = limewater; log + water = tannin. Soak, scrape, re-soak, and tan leather.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Black pajamas, bellows, a halter, and a saddle - you're dressed for a date, too bad it's with a horse.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Kill a Bear, Cow, Horse or Llama (depending on your butchery skill) until you get a Bladder. Make a leather water flask.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Significantly less cursing due to jug breakage; significantly more cursing when your flask breaks and you realize that was your last bladder.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a leather forging bib.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Not having to stand in water to forge.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Scare up 1400 units of copper and make an anvil.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: A sense of pride and accomplishment, and the ability to weld those 14 bronze ingots you've stacked over in the corner immediately afterward.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a horse grindstone</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Higher grain yields! No one starves! Yay! Plus the endless entertainment of watching a horse go in a circle.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Get high; Y > 170; and find Hemp</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Rope and Fishing Bait</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a BWM vertical windmill and a millstone.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>OPTIONAL QUEST: Make a horizontal windmill and then realize you need Gold to make gearboxes</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: not having to scrape leather manually; deafness from the CONSTANT GRINDING NOISE</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p bold="true">BRONZE AGE</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Find Bismuth and Zinc; Gold and Silver; or Tin.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Bronze (that you were making anyway)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a Bronze axe.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: You are now sentenced to chopping down hundreds of trees in order to make enough charcoal to afford to use that new Bloomery.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Find Graphite and Kaolinite.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: You can now post "I found graphite!" on r/technode or on the discord, because really - it's an accomplishment. That and you can burn a pile of it on fire clay for now, and later you'll burn out all your Kaolinite Floo Powder teleporting back and forth between your summer plantation and your winter home every 30 seconds because you forgot something, and all your graphite will be used in a Nuclear Reactor. Savor this moment, miner. Savor it, for it is quick to sublimate.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make fire clay</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: not having to use a pit kiln to mix bronze, allowing you to screw it up in new and exciting ways.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a plow.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Add shovels to it and you can leave evidence of your bad driving, in the form of paths; waste stone on 3 hoes to plow farmlands quickly, or just drag it empty over tall grass to mow the lawn. Unfortunately this quest book does not come with a friendly neighborhood 11-year-old to mow your lawn, you gotta do it yourself.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make Waystones using red gems and gold. Place waystone, give it a name. Make signposts, give them a name that matches the waystone name. Teleport from the sign to the waystone for a price of 1 Kaolinite Powder + 1 per 500m distance.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Watching your basemates deplete your Kaolinite supplies on corpse runs and needless back and forth fetch trips just before you finish making all the things that require fire clay.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>That and now all your roads are somewhat less useful, which is why the plow quest was put first.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a BWM saw</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Higher wood yields, a new death message</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p bold="true">IRON AGE</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make an iron anvil.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: You could go after that achievement where you make 4 pieces of iron armor and wear it, but honestly don't bother, you'll get iron from mob drops later. Just make a blast furnace.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a horse chopping block and a horse press</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Chopping block - Higher wood yields without the possibility of death.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Press - Paper! You can also get creosote oil early, which is nice at this stage of the game, but when you make a coke oven later you'll just have even more of a storage problem. However, you can use your nice new creosote oil to make Treated Wood Barrels.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a hopper</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: TPS lag</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make an Iron Water Flask</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Your flask now holds two buckets of water (or milk), and lasts long enough to you to forget where you put the bladders. You can also use it to see how full a steel tank is when an update clobbers your WAILA settings.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>However, we all know it's yet another thing that sits in your hotbar while you drink out of ponds.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p bold="true">STEEL AGE</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make the blast furnace block, anywhere between 12 and 60 wrought iron sheets, and a Tuyere.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Tinnitus, and a new vocabulary word to share with your friends at school when you can go again</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a blast furnace with a Crucible underneath. Spend 5 minutes pumping bellows, or pump only once in a while, or whatever that newfangled trick is that you can do in 1.12; I just wedge a coffee mug on the right mouse button of my trackball and go use the bathroom or something</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Steel</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make rudimentary RF power now that you can build an IE windmill</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: You can power your refrigerator</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a refrigerator</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Food will survive you logging out on a multiplayer server</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a TFC Tech Crucible</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: You can slow down a bit on the tree farm there, Paul Bunyan, you don't need as much charcoal now.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a TFC Tech Electric Forge</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: all your meat is now perfectly cooked at 200 C, cheap glass blocks, and efficient metal heating</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make Storage Drawers</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: An actual solution to your growing pile of storage problems</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p bold="true">COLORED STEEL AGE</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Find Nickel</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Now you can actually get to the good part of the pack. Reflect on how long it took you to find Nickel.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Mix up some Red and Blue Steel</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Freezing in the night time, but you now have a fighting chance in the Nether (Red Steel Armor)...and now you'll overheat in your own buildings in the Winter (Blue Steel Armor)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Craft an "Ultimate" (Vanilla) bucket.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: OMFG it's a vanilla bucket, you've won TFC! Now you can take ponds with you and drink out of them instead of using your flask. Sure you could do this with a red steel bucket, but now you don't have to use a separate bucket just for lava. Saved 100% inventory space over the TFC solution! BAM!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>PRO TIP: Your victory is also short-lived when you see how many recipes call for a vanilla bucket and don't give it back to you.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Nether Portal with your new black steel pick.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Glowstone, netherrack, quartz, and a sense that you should have brought your black bronze armor</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>PRO TIP: Don't anger the pigmen. Yet.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build a fort and make that a gold farm using your disused vertical windmill and saw.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: The joyous sound of Zombie Pigmen queuing to "use" the saw while you slowly dehydrate, hiding in your fort from the ghasts. It's beautiful, really.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>PRO TIP: Zombie Pigmen adore snowball fights</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p bold="true">IMMERSIVE ENGINEERING AGE</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a Metal Press</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: never having to weld two ingots EVER AGAIN.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a Crusher</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Never using a Quern again. Also, Tinnitus in your other ear.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>PRO TIP: Don't eat the horse that powers your horse grindstone.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a Pumpjack</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: The crushing realization that you're going to need to make a distillation tower for this, or at least a refinery</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a Petroleum distillation tower</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Lowered property values as your village is next to an industrial park</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a Squeezer, a Fermenter, and a Refinery</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: You can now stop throwing out all your rotten food</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a Diesel Generator</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Tinnitus in both ears and your entire household</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a mining drill</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Mining 9 unsupported blocks at a time is almost a guaranteed cave-in</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Farm Ghast Tears. Find Nether Wart. Make a Mixer, a TFC Tech Smeltery, a Blowpipe, and a Bottler. Oh, you'll need Rainwater too, see Rockhounding quests for details, only because I hate repeating myself</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Regeneration Extended (Wart -> Tear -> Redstone) is the best healing item in the game. You're gonna be sucking these down like it's your first night in Las Vegas, so make a bunch.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>PRO TIP: Ghasts love snowball fights just as much as Zombie Pigmen do!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build a solar tower and some mirrors.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: The realization that you're a vampire because you can't see yourself in the mirror</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build a Steam Turbine</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: The Tinnitus is now at "Baby Driver" levels.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>BONUS ACTION: Remembering that movie exists. Sorry not sorry.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make an Extractor. Dig out all blocks around the wheel. PUT A ROOF OVER IT THAT ISN'T RIGHT NEXT TO THE WHEEL. One slab height is not enough, has to be a full block's worth of space.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Multiple server crashes - Did you only do the first thing I said? We're not kidding. The extractor is a crashy bitch in TFC worlds. Do it right and you are rewarded.</p>
      <p>With a storage problem.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p bold="true">PNEUMATIC CRAFT</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Find sulfur</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Not having to kill creepers for gunpowder</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a pressure chamber</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Not having to blow up your iron</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a refinery</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: You weren't using those diamonds anyway. Diamonds aren't a girl's best friend; plastic is.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make an Amadron tablet</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: When you get the pun</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make an assembly line</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: 20 bar and the ability to produce pressure with RF</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a Rockhounding Precipitation Chamber and make Sodium Polyacrylate. You might have to come back to this one.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: You can make snow on demand any time of the year. Oh, that and Etching Acid. Yep, we gated the second half of PneumaticCraft behind Rockhounding. You're welcome.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make an OpenBlocks Glider with your brown plastic and Sodium Polyacrylate</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: You have been cursed to never having it on your hotbar while falling.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make PnC Armor. Become immune to temperature effects.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Finding out that the AR Space Suit (which is possibly cheaper) also does this.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p bold="true">ROCKHOUNDING</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a SimplyLoaders Raintank to start Rainwater Collection.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Water water everywhere but not a drop to drink. It's Vanilla Water!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>PRO TIP: Do not for any reason stack two SimplyLoaders Raintanks on top of each other. No. Really. Not kidding. Your world will not stop crashing the server unless you use external tools. I fixed this bug 7 months ago as of this writing and they still haven't merged it on Github.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make the TFC Tech Smeltery</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: remembering Tinker's Construct is not in the pack as you make glass bottles</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a Slurry Pond, a Gasifier Burner, Gas Purifier, and Two Power Stations. Make Syngas.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: I SPENT ALL THAT IRON ON THIS?!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a Mineral Sizer</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: All the Gangue you can carry, which means Chunkloaders.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>PRO TIP: Rockhounding Power Stations can use Charcoal and Lava (and possibly other burnables) as "Fuel" - this sounds good, until you realize exactly how inefficient using Charcoal is compared to making that Charcoal into Syngas.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a Lab Oven, an ElectroChemical CSTR, 4x Evaporation Tanks, a Leaching Controller, and another Gasifier Burner for Water Vapor. (Phew). Make Sulfuric Acid, then Hydrochloric Acid in your Lab Oven. Make Sodium Hydroxide in your CSTR. Realize that you need a good source of Rainwater. Turn Gangue into Shards.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Multiple industrial accidents and two new storage problems - holy crap that's a lot of shards, and that's a lot of leachate</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a Retention Controller, a NuclearCraft Rock Crusher, a NuclearCraft Electrolyzer, a NuclearCraft Chemical Reactor, and beg/borrow/steal some way to Hydrofluoric Acid. Turn your leachate into more shards.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: The realization that 200mb of High-Grade Leachate turns into 1000mb of Toxic Waste, and an even bigger storage problem - none of these shards are the same as the other ones I made earlier</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a Chemical Extractor, a Reforming Tower, and a NuclearCraft Chemical Reactor. Also a NuclearCraft Nitrogen Collector</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: turn all your shards into Metal Dusts, and a new storage problem - where am I gonna put all this Cadmium and Phosphorous, and what is this Lutetium stuff anyway</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a Metal Alloyer</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Actual upgraded filters on your leachate controller &amp; retention controller, so you can actually choose the shard you want instead of the "all of them" setting you're using currently</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Oh wow I can make Colored Steel in this?</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Oh I can make Wrought Iron at the cost of 1 charcoal per 10 ingots? Pinch me</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Speed upgrades and more industrial accidents as you realize you tuned your pipe network around the slow machine speeds</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p bold="true">NuclearCraft</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Find a pitchblende vein</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Nickel 2.0™</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>BONUS ACTION: At least Granite rocks are prettier than Gabbro.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Mine some pitchblende</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Guys is radiation bad?</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Throw the pitchblende into your crusher</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: One pitchblende crushes into 9 Uranium Dust, netting you enough nuclear material to power a small country for a year. For you, it won't be enough.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>PRO TIP: Get a spot in the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>BONUS ACTION: If you're on the official test server, hit me up for some Rad-Away. I might have you gather mushrooms though. My base glows in the dark but it's not from the radiation.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make some basic plating</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Empty space in your Graphite and Lead storage</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make an Alloy Furnace</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: The realization that all of your Black Steel is going to make Ferroboron</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: make a Geiger Counter</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Glorious silence...for now</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make some Advanced plating</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Empty space in your Lithium and Redstone storage</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: make a Universal Bin</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Looks prettier than a trashcan next to your Turbine. Silicon Carbide being an ingot will remind you Mekanism isn't in the pack</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a Separator</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: A new storage problem; this is the one where all the things are radioactive</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make some Depleted Uranium plating</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: non-zero radiation levels</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make some Elite Plating</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Actually making a Radiation Scrubber</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make some rad-away fluid</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Glowing yellow mushrooms all over your base</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make Light Radiation Shielding</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Now you can make Medium Radiation Shielding</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make Medium Radiation Shielding</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Now you can make Heavy Radiation Shielding</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make Heavy Radiation Shielding and apply it to your Space Suit or PnC Armor</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Not dying in 15 seconds after picking up Prometheum by accident</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Find Manganese, Magnesium, and Boron</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: More ingots to store in a chest somewhere; also you can make batteries and the turbine</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Mine a lot of Zirconium and make -ZA fuel</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: If you don't have at least 3 stacks of Zirconium dust AFTER alloying all your fuel, repeat this quest until you do</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Completely deplete 3 nearest Zirconium veins to power your thirsty IE Excavator</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: A reminder to look at JEI, because NuclearCraft's Rock Crusher has a chance to turn Diorite rocks into Zirconium dust. Thankfully you hoarded all mined cobblestone in these handy storage drawers instead of throwing it all away eve̵r̶y̷ ̸t̵i̸m̴ë̴̙́,̷͔̓ ̸̼͆r̴̺͊i̵͇͋ḡ̸̨ḩ̸̛̮̹̮̖̺̯̞͛̈́́̈́͑͌̓͠ţ̷̹͓̠͇͓͈̱̂́̈́ͅ?̴̺̝̙̹̈́̀ ̶̢͖̱͈͖̠̜͕̱͗͠R̶̡̳͈͎̼͓͈͓͎͚̭̦͖̗͍̼̮̖͚̗͓̳̥͕̬̗̱̦̳̺͓͍͍̣̼̿͂́̀̿̏͐́̏̓̏̒̈͐̀̀̈͒̆̓͠I̴̢̧̢̛̤͈̙͙̹̬̦̠͕̳͖͚̰͌̔̾̈̓̈́̀̃̔̂̓͛̈̇́̊̃́́̃̕̕͜͠͝͠͠ͅĢ̴̡̧̢̛͈̳̣̘̠͈̪̯̗̖͚̪̮͔͎͓̦͔͚̳͇͍̳̖̬̣̣̱̗̔̉̊͂͊͋̓͂̔̃̌̿͌̀̒̅͊̂͌͆̅̽͗̅̕͝͠͝Ḩ̴̛̜̗͙̰͉̲̥̜̀̏̐̌̀̀̒̈̔̓̊̿̈́̀́̓̚T̷̨̠̻̰̖̝͕̥͉͍̖̯̰̹͗͜ͅ?̴̧̪̝͙̳̱͆̈́͛͘͠</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a Decay Hastener</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Oh crap that released radiation into the world? WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make some radium neutron sources</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: 90% efficiency (up from 0%)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make Upgraded Power Storage</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Does the tier 3 battery really leak radiation into the world? (YES, but it's a small amount.)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build a Compact Water Source</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: a crushing realization you can't easily and sustainably convert Rain Water into Fresh Water</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build a Dense Water Source</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: An understanding of what few things Rainwater is used for</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make Heavy Water and fill some Empty Frames with it</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: A smugness that you can build heavy water moderators whereas in most packs with NuclearCraft everyone is stuck using Beryllium and Graphite. That smugness is soon tempered by the realization that there is no efficiency bonus.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build an XNet controller and a few advanced connectors to shuttle power and HPS around</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Lagging the server for a good 30 seconds with a single shift-click</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build a Reactor Controller and Fuel Cells</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: A sparkly new bucket of Corium</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build a working nuclear reactor</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>2 hours on YouTube later...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: One! Two! Three! Four! Four Buckets of Corium! Ah, ah, ah.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build a Turbine. Hook universal bin to output port.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: 13691 RF/t</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Make a Fuel Reprocessor</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: a chest full of 1-8 depleted fuel pellets of various types</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Mine some Thorium</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: A couple of hours of frustration sitting in front of the NC Reactor Planner trying to make a decent Irradiator Design</p>
      <p>PRO TIP: Yes, if you put Thorium in your Rockhounding Chemical Extractor you *will* get more Thorium than just combining it into scrap. I would consider cranking the Intensity to 16. (I usually leave it at 10 for Nice Round Numbers™, it's profitable even at 10.)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Turn Thorium into Protactinium-Enriched Thorium (TBP), turn that into TBU, then use that as fuel and reprocess it</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Neptunium and a new pretty color of isotopes to store (Neptunium is required to complete the tech tree.)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Turn bismuth into Polonium, make some Po-Be sources</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Radiation sickness and 95% efficiency</p>
      <p>BONUS ACTION: This is one of the more useful deadly things you've made</p>
      <p>PRO TIP: It takes longer to make Polonium than TBP. Be patient.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Melt sugar into molten sugar, mix with water in Chemical Reactor to make Ethanol</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Nuclear Exclusion Zone around your Base (This bug was fixed)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p bold="true">ADVANCED ROCKETRY</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build a Lathe</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Making pistons without heating metal is its own reward.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build an Electrolyzer</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: A new interesting storage problem and the ability to fill up the Oxygen in your space suit so it doesn't look like a lit cigarette</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build a Cutting Machine</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Highest yield cutting planks, and a new death message because you can't stop standing on it</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build a Chemical Reactor</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Silicon Boules</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build that processing assembly line thingie</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: A cute little factory animation and cheaper AR crafting components for all the machines you already built</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build a rolling machine</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: An inferior metal press that's stuck on "Plate" and requires water, but you're not going to space without it</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build a Satellite Builder</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: We still don't know who watches the watchers, but we know who built the builder.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build a launch pad</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: A complaint from the local township committee about your zoning violations</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build a rocket</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: the realization that no wiki has been updated for "Bipropellant" rockets yet</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p bold="true">OPEN COMPUTERS</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build a computer case</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: You teach your kid a few new swear words when the recipe eats your 'Hard' Hammer (yes I reported it)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: build a Screen</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Now your bird has a few chosen phrases to repeat at the screen recipe eats another hammer (reported this one too). T3 is also one of the few blocks that uses Pitchblende that isn't radioactive.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: build a Keyboard</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: now you can interact with a computer you haven't finished building yet. Appreciate the realism as you realize you have to make nearly all 101 keys yourself.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: build a Power Convertor</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: now you can actually power the computer that won't boot yet. Curse as you realize that your computer should be moved up/down 1m and you have to break &amp; replace everything</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: build a graphics card, CPU, ram, a hard disk, and maybe a redstone card or something</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: your raw materials chests are a little emptier, but hey, at least all the slots are filled</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: build an OpenOS disk AND an EPROM</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: IT BOOTS!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: build a Reactor Computer Port and a Turbine Computer Port</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: Spend 3 hours looking for a program to control your reactor</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build an internet card</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: actually download and use the program</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>QUEST: Build an RS latch using designs from the minecraft wiki and use your existing XNet setup to control redstone outputs instead of this OpenComputers thingie</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>REWARD: about 5 hours saved</p>
      </section>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id="storage">
    <section>
      <p bold="true">TFC Storage</p>
      <p space="2"/>
      <link ref="index" color="#CC3333">&lt;- Index</link>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Adds metal crates, food shelves, preserving jars, meat hangers and grain piles to TerraFirmaCraft: The Next Generation</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Food Shelves - Made out of wood, can hold any type of food, provides a 0.8x decay modifier generally and another 0.5x modifier when underground (below y 140 and shielded from sunlight)</p>
      <p>Meat Hangers - Made out of wood too, can hold cooked meat, cheese and garlic, provides a 0.6x decay modifier generally and another 0.5x when underground like the food shelves.</p>
      <p>Preserving jars - Made out of glass and a tin cap, can hold any food that can be pickled, provides a 0.09x modifier when filled with vinegar and holding a pickled food item.</p>
      <p>Grain Piles - Like log piles, shift click on the ground with a grain item (wheat, barley etc.) and it will place a grain pile with a capacity of 16. Create silos and shelter those pile from direct sunlight to add a modifier of 0.4x to them</p>
      <p>Metal crates - made out of wrought iron, these crates act just like chests with 27 x 3 inventory spaces, but when put together up to 27, you can use the search bar to filter items in the entire crate system. You can easily have a warehouse with a few crate piles dedicated to different types of items and always just search for what you want to get.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Food shelves and hangers need to have 0 sunlight to be considered cool, grain piles need to have sunlight less than 15 to be considered sheltered (just having a roof above helps)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Generally</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Right-clicking on a block from the mod inserts the stack you are holding into it,</p>
      <p>Left-clicking extracts one item</p>
      <p>Shift left-clicking extracts the whole stack.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Due to how TFC food stacking works, you are not allowed to insert more items in a block that already has items. If you want to fill it more, extract the items, stack them using the TFC hotkey for food stacking and insert them all back.</p>
    </section>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id="progression">
    <section>
      <p bold="true">Biletooth's TNFC Progression</p>
      <p space="2"/>
      <link ref="index" color="#CC3333">&lt;- Index</link>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">TNFC is rather daunting with many ways to progress. To get you started, <link href="https://old.reddit.com/r/Technode/comments/icjt8r/technodefirmacraft_progression/">Biletooth chronicles</link> how he progressed through TNFC.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Note that this is just my way of progressing and I highly recommend you carve your own path. There is no guide for TNFC but by combining the information pinned in the TNFC discord channels and using JEI you should be able to figure everything out. TNFC works with TFC 1.12 now, there is many changes from classic and I recommend looking at the 1.12 changes wiki page to clarify this.
        <link href="https://tng.terrafirmacraft.com/Differences_From_Classic">TFC Differences from Classic</link>
      </p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>For the TFC part there is also a well implemented Patchouli book available. Finally I recommend taking a look at the modlist of TNFC and searching in JEI with @[modname] to see what the mod has to offer and go from there. Some general tips include: looking up what kind of rare resources you need for certain mods (like redstone, lapiz, glowstone or even nickel for black steel etc.) and only start progressing in those mods when you know you have access to them. In that regard I also highly recommend playing on a server so you can trade for resources if you don’t find them. Tool progression is very important in this pack, different tiers of Hammers/chisels/saws WILL unlock different recipes. The higher tier machines won’t be craftable with a low tier tool.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Now onto my actual progression.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>It all starts with base TFC. Again this is totally up to you how you progress through TFC. I made the 'challenge' for myself to not look at better ways of getting steel before I had made a full, max capacity TFC blast furnace for example. If you're new to TFC or new to TFC 1.12 I recommend reading through the new manual for it. I personally spend the first in game year exploring for several key resources and a base location.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The first venture into mods other than TFC started for me after steel. At this point you can start making Yabba barrels and organise your storage better. I also started to look at some BmW features like the windmill for a saw and a grindstone and a bit later I decided to look at the Horsepower horse press and horse grindstone. After that I progress my way up to black steel. When reaching black steel tier, and more specifically a black steel hammer and chisel, I looked at Immersive Engineering. Getting the metal press is a huge quality of life upgrade from base TFC and I recommend getting it early. When the age of IE starts there's lots to do. There’s several energy generating options where I started with windmills and waterwheels. When I had a basic power setup I looked at the Electric crucible and Electric forge which again are a massive Quality of Life item. The vanilla steel furnace and IE Crusher is also on this list.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Somewhere around this time I teched up further to red/blue steel tier and made the appropriate anvil, tools and buckets. Then I tried out the diesel generator with an IE refinery and pump jack when I had a steady supply of diesel I made an excavator and spend the next couple of in game days scouting for deposits and harvesting them. To conclude the energy track I constructed a steam turbine with solar towers. There’s also the furnace track in IE which starts with the coke oven and crude blast furnace and eventually ends in the Arc furnace. There's lots of other stuff in IE which I haven't done yet or that I could have done earlier, again here, take a look at what the mod has to offer and what you want to focus on, IE also has a great in game manual. I "ended" Immersive Engineering by making the mining drill, 3 excavators and another pump jack not connected to the refinery for raw oil. The whole systems runs on a steam turbine with 4 solar towers and 2 steel tanks that store excess steam to get through the night. It generates 12k rf/t which I split into 2x6k lines, 1 line for 1 excavator an Arc furnace and misc machines (connected to a big capacitor battery and not using everything at the same time). The other 6k lines goes to the two other excavators and an RF flux generator.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>This flux generator leads me to the next mod I looked at, Pneumaticcraft. This was the first time I ever played with PnC and I loved every second of it. I highly recommend checking out its guidebook and the YouTube videos of Danny and Son. To get the flux generator you basically have to progress through the whole mod. Starting with getting the pressure chamber, oil refinery, plastic maker and the machines that make the circuit board. You will need advanced pressure to complete this track. Once I had the right infrastructure for it I created several of its nifty items like the Amadron tablet, omnidirectional hoppers, logistics drones (a whole topic on its own, great for storage) and finally I spend a lot of time on making the PNC armor and it's upgrades. I also tried out the pneumatic elevator to reach a place 40 blocks up, it’s not the greatest lift tbh but it is very immersive and I quite enjoy using it. The PNC track got concluded for me after making the upgraded armor set and crafting the Ariel interface (note you will have to go to the nether for this). Many things require plastic so this is a mod I frequently return to. Again check JEI and its manual to see all the stuff it has to offer, I probably missed most of it!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>We’re coming up to the point where I currently am. I was debating between checking out RH and AR and went with the latter. AR has a very unique progression imo but it’s not well documented. There is a great video series on YouTube by Thorgal Daily Gaming where I got all my knowledge from, there’s also a wiki. At this point I made all the multiblock structures needed to make space infrastructure. I haven't yet build a rocket or the machines to fuelling it. I have however been to space as I play on the server and I 'bought' a subscription from another player where he build me a space elevator at my base and I pay him for using it to get access to space. I did notice you could build the 'lathe' from AR a lot earlier in this pack as it automates the making of rods (needed for rails and pistons) so you could make it a lot earlier if you wanted to automate this. AR progression is the only way to reach the End! So if you need stuff from the End this is the way.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>So that leaves me with the mods I haven't touched yet and there’s quite a lot of them that I could have already started and could have sped up my progress in other paths but such is the way of the sandbox. In particular XNet’s cable system seems to be very powerful but I have yet to explore it. RH has a whole progression path I still have to look at as well. That concludes my main tech progression so far.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>There’s several smaller mods that can aid you with several mods or that give a huge quality of life upgrade. The ones I've tested in this are: Wearable Backpacks, Waterflasks (recommend teching up to flask asap), a fishing rod for early food (tweaked recipe, use JEI), some BmW stuff, Waystone teleporting and some chisel and bits. There’s several smaller mods that I don’t know or haven’t used like Advanced Hook Launchers, AstikorCarts (great for animals and path making), First Aid bandages (I use hot spring healing and avoiding combat ;^) ), Immersive Cables, Just a Few Fish, Animal nets, OpenBlocks stuff and Simply Jetpacks.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
    </section>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id="rockhounding">
    <section>
      <p bold="true">Rockhounding Tips by Benanov</p>
      <link ref="index" color="#CC3333">&lt;- Index</link>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Rockhounding is rather complicated. To get you started, here are some <link href="https://old.reddit.com/r/Technode/comments/jne6d2/benanovs_rockhounding_chemistry_tips">starting tips</link> from our resident RH expert.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Expect to need to stockpile a lot of resources to get a meaningful operation off the ground. Save those Uninspected Minerals!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Mineral Sizer requires fuel (Syngas). Lava will work but honestly you want Syngas.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Flue Gas won't work, but considering I use the same setup is to make Flue Gas and Syngas. The RH setup machine guide has a small annotation about whether a machine requires RF or Fuel.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fun fact: The Electrochemical CSTR requires both for all recipes in the TNFC pack</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Syngas for the Lazy</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>So you want to set up Syngas, but don't want the discovery of figuring it all out yourself? Look no further.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You need Fresh Water. An Immersive Engineering Pump or Rockhounding Water Pump are good choices, but my favorite is the PneumaticCraft Liquid Hopper with a dispenser upgrade. It's a little on the expensive side, but it requires zero RF and will keep up with the demands of multiple machines (plus you can make speed ugprades). You'll want the standard infinite 2x2 sink if you're placing your own water sources. Remember to cover the water with pipes or a slab so it doesn't freeze.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Make a Slurry Pond. Set the concentration to 10%. That will use 4 solids at a time to make quite a bit of output. The higher concentrations use less solids and take less time, but don't give you as much output. This is silly. We're making the fuel that the rest of your lab runs on; you want to maximize your liquid output. Don't start making slurry until you've finished placement.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>For Coal users: Make a Mineral Sizer to make Cracked Coal. You need Coal Blocks, so that means Bituminous Coal. Don't be an exploiter and use NuclearCraft to craft Bituminous Coal from Graphite. (Bonus points to anyone who then uses the Coal Tar compound to create more Graphite, but you won't profit from this; you don't get enough Coal Tar compound.)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Make a Gasifier Burner. Place your slurry pond in such a way that you can pipe the output into the top tank. (Now you can start making slurry.) Feed fresh water into the bottom tank ofthe burner, and fresh water into the slurry pond itself. One Liquid Hopper or IE pump can feed both. If you're using Rotten Flesh you can skip the Particulate Collector. I recommend putting one in eventually, so you can use this setup to process Toxic Waste and Coal, but in the beginning if you're using solely rotten flesh, you can skip having to make the 6 bottles.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Make a Gas Purifier. Note that the "output" Pressure Vessel from the Burner can be the "input" Vessel for the Purifier. Saved you a vessel, you're welcome. You will want the Particulate Collector here for Fly Ash, which can be hydrated then smelted to make bricks for a Refractory Upgrade, which makes the Burner hold its temperature (costing you less fuel).</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Store the output in a Gas Holder. Put a Gas Pump on the output of the holder, and run Gas ducts to all the INPUTs (the back) of your Power Stations. Turn the pump ON.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Bootstrapping</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Okay but Power Stations run on fuel, Benanov! How do we get them hot enough to make fuel? Well thankfully the Power Stations will also run on lava, but really inefficiently. You'll want to put about 3-4 buckets of lava (it'll convert all the lava to fuel units, then you put another in, and another in) until you can't put in any more.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Turn on the Purifier first. Then turn on the Gas Burner, and continue to put lava in the Gas Burner Power Station until you the Syngas tank is relatively full.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Remember to turn the burner off when you're out of slurry.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You're gonna want about 3-4 stacks of flesh or cracked coal.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The orientation of machines does matter in RH. If there's a blue arrow or orange arrow you need to make sure you're facing the correct way when placing the block.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>And servers are generally not required for machines, as far as i can tell. The Chemical Extractor and Mineral Sizer run fine without them. Servers are great for "do this X number of times" jobs - which is why I use it for the Metal Alloyer (otherwise it'll convert all of my element cabinet contents to White Gold or something).</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>IMO the Syngas setup is the first thing you should build in RH. Don't start chasing shards until you have a Gas Holder (not a mere pressure vessel) with at least a pixel of Syngas. (When you see how much Gas Holders hold, you'll understand.)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">A Note about Salt</p>
      <p>Salt is a valuable material in TechNode. You can use it to preserve food and it is an absolutely essential ingredient for two very important liquids in the Rockhounding Mineral cycle - Hydrochloric Acid and Sodium Cyanide. While you can also use salt to create Salt Water, this is generally not necessary.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>If you live in Rock Salt or have it nearby, great! If not you will need to spend some time making the Rockhounding Evaporation Tank and the Seasoning Rack. You will not be able to meaningfully do this until you can work Wrought Iron into ingots.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The Rockhounding Evaporation Tank has many modes, accessible with the Mod Wrench. For making salt, you do not need the wrench. (You will require one later to make Evaporation Tanks export Saturated Brine, an ingredient for Sodium Hydroxide.)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The Profiling Bench is required to make almost every other machine, and will be one of the first things you create. It does not require power to run. To change modes, punch it. To use it, place an item into it with right-click. To extract the product, right-click again.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">A note about Sulfur</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Sulfur is a common extract from a lot of shards and relatively easy to select for even without filter upgrades, but until you start pulling sulfur out of your chemical extractor, you're going to want a few stacks of the yellow stinky stuff.</p>
      <p>If you can't find any, turn Bituminous Coal into Syngas and check your Particulate Collectors.</p>
      <p>Another option for obtaining Sulfur is recycling Toxic Waste. You can use an existing Syngas setup but you'll want a separate output vessel for the Flue Gas.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>A word of warning: Do not fill your cistern to capacity with Toxic Waste! Process it a few buckets at a time.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">My Machine Isn't Processing!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Many different parts of a machine require consumables. Common things to check besides power source are Slurry Agitators, Crushing Gears, Test Tubes, Graduated Cylinders, and Catalysts. All liquids and gases must be present in order for a machine to run.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>If your machine is running but keeps resetting its progress halfway through, you're out of power. Machines that require RF can have their power source upgraded with a Gas Turbine to burn Syngas to generate RF. (We have not found this to be a good method for generating RF to run the rest of your base.)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">What is that Explosion?</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Pressure Vessels only hold 1,000 Cu (the equivalent of 1,000 mB) of gas. This is a surprisingly small amount. Consider upgrading to a Gas Holder, or shut off the input to that Pressure Vessel and dump the contents.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">There's Green Stuff all Over my Base!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Congratulations, you've had your first industrial accident. Don't store pollutant fluids in Rockhounding tanks for any long period of time and do not allow a tank to be filled to capacity. With pollutant gases you have fewer options.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>PneumaticCraft Liquid Hoppers are incredibly useful for this purpose.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>I have found that the Lab Oven's Fluid Output system requires all of the Product to be drained before the Waste will export. If your output systems are not fast enough at picking up the Product, the Toxic Waste will build up and leak all over your lab.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Chemical Extractor</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>This is my notes for the entire Chemical Extraction Process, from Uninspected Mineral to Elemental Dust. This is done entirely from memory without the game in front of me, you've been warned.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Make the following machines:</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>I will assume you have a working Syngas setup.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>First a Lab Blender. RH requires some initial processing to take the ingredients from other mods to get started. Lab Blenders run on RF and can be extracted with hoppers, conveyor belts, or lackey.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Second, you'll also want a Lab Oven. Feed it plenty of Fresh Water and RF.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Third, build the Mineral Sizer. In it, Uninspected Minerals are turned into Gangue. Gangue is a fancy word for "stuff we don't want that's attached to stuff we do want" - you pick the Communition Level and that yields a particular type of Gangue. If you did Bituminous Coal for Syngas, you already made one of these, as you need it for Cracked Coal.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Which type do you want? Pick an element you want. Example: Lead. Search for "Lead" and you will see all the shards that make Lead. In JEI pay attention to what Gangues yield Lead.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>I started with Sulfide as I thought I'd need tons of Sulfur. Honestly one might have better luck with Native. If this is your first batch, it really doesn't matter as you don't have filter upgrades.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The path branches here. However, for both paths, you need Sulfuric Acid from the Lab Oven. My recommendation: make the Vanadium Catalyst as soon as you can if you have the Arc Furnace available (or borrow someone's). It doubles your output. The problem is - you can't do this until you get usable Vanadium from your extractor. In the short term, harvest some Sulfur. You will be hitting the Chloride Bearing Compound pretty hard too, so stock up the blender.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You also need Water Vapor which is made in the Gasifier Burner by feeding Fresh Water into both chambers. I honestly made a second burner (you don't need the purifier on this one) to load a Gas Holder full of vapor so I didn't have to keep mucking with the Syngas setup, but if you make enough vapor you're good for a long while. 80,000 cu lasted quite a while.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Finally you'll need a source of Rainwater. In the amounts you'll need? Make the NuclearCraft infinite water source. The lowest tier is fine.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Path One, the easy path:</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Stick your Gangues in the Slurry Pond with Sulfuric Acid. As your Slurry Pond was already created because you have Syngas, hey look another machine you can re-use! This yields Leachate. Jump down to where you see "Leachate" again. Be quick about it.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Path Two, the Harder Path, the one I originally followed:</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Okay, we have Gangue. Now we need a Leaching Controller.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Leaching Controllers need four fluids (3 liquids, 1 gas) in order to function.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Sodium Hydroxide is created by mixing Saturated Brine (TFC brine will not work) and Fresh Water in an Electrochemical CSTR. You can get Saturated Brine by using the Mod Wrench on Evaporation Tanks until they spit out "Brine" - I think it's stage 3. Use a RH pump to extract the brine from the tanks and route that sucker to the Fluid Input system on the CSTR. Because Saturated Brine is made via rainstorm, I used a Liquid Hopper and an OpenBlocks tank to hold enough as a buffer for when I wanted to make some when it wasn't raining. NaOH is not a pollutant, but you'll want quite a bit of it.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Hydrochloric Acid is made in the Lab Oven. You'll want to make Sulfuric Acid first. There's no catalyst for HCl, so have lots of salt handy.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>And finally, you need Rainwater.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You also need Water Vapor. Note you need TWO pressure vessels of Water Vapor. Two Gas Holders would be a little ridiculous.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Okay, so now you can turn Gangue into Shards. You also get Leachate. At this point you don't need to process your Leachate (whereas on the "easy" path, you do).</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Leachate is a pollutant. Get it out of that Buffer Tank as soon as possible (ideally, have a way to do this that is set up before you start running the machines!)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>In the Rentention Vat (Retention Controller), you can process Leachate for even more shards; some shards don't come from Gangue, but only from Leachate. Greicite (pure Lithium) only comes from Leachate, and that was my big win here.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You'll need Water Vapor to run the controller, as well as Rainwater.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You'll also need Hydrofluoric Acid. There are two ways to get Hydrofluoric Acid:</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The first is the Lab Oven. You can turn Sulfuric Acid into Hydrofluoric Acid if you live near Granite. Mine out Raw Granite, run it through Mineral Sizer, and hey look, Fluorite Bearing Compound, and Bob's your Uncle. Easy.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The second is a little bit circumlocuitous - this is the way I did it, because I'm stupid and forgot to get Raw Granite while mining for Redstone. You need either Villaumite or Loose Granite Rocks. Stuff the NuclearCraft rock crusher full of your haul and pull the Villaumite dust you get out (also, hey, sulfur!) and refine it in the manufactory until you get Sodium Fluoride. I think at this point it's a NuclearCraft Fluid Infuser, then a NuclearCraft Chemical Reactor, and then a few other steps. You'll want a NuclearCraft Electrolyzer too to make Hydrogen. If you're lucky enough to find Villaumuite, you can skip the rock crusher but not the manufactory. Follow a bunch of steps in JEI and you should end up with a way to make the Hydrofluoric Acid you need.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Once the machine is up and running, pump in a SMALL amount of Leachate into the Flotation tank, about 200mB. If you use a PneumaticCraft Liquid Hopper set to "redstone high" mode, and use a button to momentarily pass in a redstone signal, you will import 300mb. Hit the button twice and that's enough for 3 runs of the machine.)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The bigger problem is that 200mB of Leachate becomes 1000mB of Toxic Waste. Be ready to store a LOT of Toxic Waste until you can process it later (or void it).</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Be sure to put hoppers on your specimen collectors. The machine will not do batch #2 until the product from batch #1 is extracted. Also without fine filter meshes, you are going to get a really wide range of shards if you pick certain specific gravities. Have enough storage for that. Seriously - you're gonna get a giant pile of shards if you pick the middle. There is an argument for doing this - I did it that way for fun and then processed them all.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Also, water vapor DOES cause Pressure Vessels to explode, which scares guests and will hurt you minorly (my entirely green body went yellow, but I didn't take enough damage to suffer slowness or fatigue effects). The best fix to that is to have a regen potion on hand or just be near a hot spring. I haven't figured out a good system for keeping both sets of pressure vessels (the two on the leaching controller and the one on the retention vat) filled when I want them and not filling when I don't want them. Right now I'm just breaking pipes and turning off the main shutoff valve. </p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Now we've got our shards and it's time to step up to the really difficult portion of the machine cycle. Yes. Seriously. I know, you've spent all this time reading it and you still don't have useful output - Most shards aren't very useful at this point unless you make the 100% carbon shards (then you can make graphite in small quantities if you also made Coal Syngas)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The Chemical Extractor requires four things to work.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>First, you need Ferrous Catalysts. I've processed about maybe 1,000 shards and I'm still on my first set. Do you have 6 wrought iron ingots? That's all you need.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Second, you need Glassware - test tubes and graduated cylinders. These are consumed slowly by the process, so have spares handy. Enchanting these with Unbreaking does work, something to keep in mind for the future.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Now you need two liquids. Both are made from Liquid Ammonia. I hate this stuff. Of all the chemical spills on my base, the majority were from this. You WILL respect Liquid Ammonia; whether you do it by default or by repeated lessons is up to you.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The easiest and safest way to make Liquid Ammonia is to use NuclearCraft to make it - in the Chemical Reactor. Use an Electrolyzer to feed in the Hydrogen, and one Nitrogen Collector to feed in the Nitrogen. Save the Oxygen. As for the Deuterium, that's useful in NuclearCraft, but not for your Rockhounding Lab. Liquid Ammonia takes a bit to make with this process, but it's 100% safe and you can easily batch up 16 buckets in a hopper and 16 buckets in the machine's output tank.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The first actual liquid ingredient to make is Sodium Cyanide. NaCN is made in the Lab Oven. Make yourself a Graphite Catalyst ASAP. It's cheap and you want it. This is the other reason you need tons of salt. You don't need to use a button to dump in the amount of fluid slowly - you can let this one pour in a little faster, but again don't back up the Fluid Input System. I use a 4x or higher speed upgrade and I can chew through 16 buckets of Liquid Ammonia before any of it spills.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You need a lot of this liquid - no matter how you set your Chemical Extractor, you always nice twice the amount of NaCN as compared to...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The second is Nitric Acid. Nitric Acid is a pollutant. Nitric Acid requires a large machine, the Reforming Controller. One thing you'll note is that you don't actually need ALL the pressure vessels it calls for. You only need two (and the buffer tank up top). You DO, however, need all 10 catalysts. Only certain catalysts are available for each recipe. You can't use Osmium Catalysts for Nitric Acid, for example. You can make Ammonia in this machine, but why? You have a 100% safe option in the Chemical Reactor.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>So let's talk about how to get the two ingredients into the machine. You will want two Gas Expansion machines. The Oxygen one is pretty easy. Fill the top tank with Liquid Oxygen, and turn it on. You can just leave it on and powered. The Pressure Vessel will never explode. It will sip fuel and sip Liquid Oxygen and turn it into Oxygen Gas and be very well behaved. After all, you have all this leftover oxygen from the Electrolyzer.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The Ammonia one is where you need to have some respect. My suggestion is two-fold: First, a button mechanism to inject 300mb into the buffer tank is sufficient for the amounts you need to make a good quantity of Nitric Acid. Second, do not be afraid to dump the tank and the pressure vessel on this side. Liquid Ammonia, once you start being able to make it in quantity, is pretty cheap. Dumping less than 300mB of liquid is a lot cheaper than 5-6 stupid deaths or being poisoned down to a sliver of health.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>So now you need catalysts. If the machine is not working but has ingredients and RF, well...it won't work without catalysts.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fuzzy on these, need more research. I never mixed and matched catalysts within the same category.NiAl catalysts = 1x? - a good argument for Metal Alloyer early, and it's just Nickel and Aluminum, no fancy trace elements. You should be able to make this with only an IE Crusher.Graphite catalysts = 2x? - If you have an Arc Furnace, these are super cheap.White gold catalysts = 3x</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Gold catalysts = 1x - cheap and easyPlatinum catalysts = 2x - hey look, a use for platinum!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Phew! That's all 4 ingredients.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Then pick a shard, and pick an "Intensity" level. I just picked 10 so that the liquid amounts would all even out. I'm not exactly sure what this does, but higher intensity requires more liquid, so I would presume you get more minerals per shard.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Then watch your elements cabinet slowly fill. You can move the Cabinet to the Metal Alloyer and it'll keep inventory. To extract the dusts (in the order they were created), hook a hopper to your Lab Balance, and put a graduated cylinder in the top half of the Elements Cabinet.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Be sure to cackle loudly as your chest fills.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>SCIENCE!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>I have never had the Nitric Acid in the fluid input system leak. It'll leak from the output tank of the Reforming Reactor, though.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Now that you have a pile of dust, what to do with it?</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Dial-An-Element</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The shards at the ends of the spectrum of specific gravity are easier to isolate. For everything else, there's...</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Leaching Filter Upgrades</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You want two Tier 5 Leaching Filter Upgrades - one for the Leaching Controller, one for the Retention Vat. This will allow you to turn the giant shard lists into just lists of 1-3 shards.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>As an example: can't find lithium? Dial in Greicite shards and turn all your Leachate into Lithium dust.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Didymium Glass</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>This relatively hard glass (it's not ghast proof, sadly, because it looks badass in the Nether) is a nice prestige item and will allow you to force your visitors to view your lab through rose-colored glass. I mean, it is Pink. Laugh. It's funny.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>It's also an ingredient for the Infernal Enchanter.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Catalysts</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Vanadium gets you more Sulfuric Acid. You need exactly one catalyst and the Arc Furnace.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Fly Ash</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>This byproduct from your syngas production should be hoarded until you get 64. Then make the Refractory Upgrade to provide better insulation to your burner. I've lost an upgrade after a chemical spill on your burner, so do be careful.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Carbon Dust</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>There's no other way to make a CO2 scrubber than making Carbon Dust and running the Arc Furnace. IMO the easiest way to get a pile of Carbon dust - more than you'll know what to do with - is by refining Toxic Waste.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Speed Upgrades</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Some machines eat more fuel with speed upgrades, or consume more precursor at a time (meaning you need to pull the upgrade to use that last little bit of Toxic Waste in the cistern). Others...there is no reason not to upgrade. Be sure your fluid transport systems can keep up with the load!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Metal Alloys</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>RH adds a lot of metal alloys; as the pack progresses many will be required for additional recipes, and older methods of obtaining the metal alloys will be removed. Expect to build one.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>You can (as of version 42) make TFC Metal Alloys, like Rose Gold, Black Bronze, etc. in the Metal Alloyer. Tungsten Steel is comparatively expensive. You won't be able to make it the old way soon, so get ready to make lots of Red Steel!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The Elements and Material Cabinets retain their contents when broken, so you can fill from a Chemical Extractor and then move the two cabinets over to a Metal Alloyer with no loss. If you don't want to do the entire Extraction setup you can fill your cabinets via Graduated Cylinders.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The server is amazingly useful for the Metal Alloyer and of all the RH machines available this is the one I recommend plugging a server into. Server Files are not cheap, but are infinitely reusable and reprogrammable. Remember to turn the server ON if you want the Alloyer to run your batches - otherwise it'll just continuously make alloys until it's out of ingredients.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>I have noticed a bunch of off-by-one errors. I think it's because a partially completed ingot will be allowed to finish before starting the batch.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>NOTE: Do not break either the Elements or Materials Cabinets while connected to an active Metal Alloyer. This will crash your game/server!</p>




    </section>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id="seedfinding">
    <section>
      <p bold="true">Finding a Decent TFC Seed</p>
      <link ref="index" color="#CC3333">&lt;- Index</link>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p><link href="https://old.reddit.com/r/Technode/comments/i6juqe/how_to_find_a_good_tfc_seed/">Original Reddit Article</link></p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Probably one of the most requested and source of most complaints in early TFC/TNFC is finding the resources one needs to progress. As this is a much more involved, complicated and possibly time-consuming process, I thought I'd go over my own process for finding what I consider a good seed for our server and share it.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>A big change with TFC version 165+ is the ability to change the size of the rock layers. You may find turning down the size of the rock layers to 4 works better for single player play. As the change results in a zoomed out rock layer, it will look identical to the seedmaker results outlined below, just the image represents a smaller area.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>For simplicity sake I'll refer to TFC, the advice I provide will also apply to Technodefirmacraft, wherever there are specific differences applicable only to the modpack, I will try and indicate. Otherwise, the advice is pretty universal to TFC Minecraft. Also note that all my advice is somewhat more specifically tied to the 1.12.2 TFC-NG versions. Although the general advice will of course be applicable to older TFC versions.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Step 1 - Know the Problem -</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>First, the background. TFC as a complete Minecraft makeover mod, changes the way the worldgen works to such a large extend that it's helpful to just forget everything you know about choosing a good Minecraft map. The key to progression in TFC is understanding rock types.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Rather than Minecraft's 'Stone', in TFC you have 22 different types of rock. These are divided into 4 types of rock (Sedimentary, Metamorphic, Igneous Extrusive and Igneous Intrusive). The rocks are world generated in 3 layers. All 22 rock types can appear at the top layer, but in the 2 deeper layers, only some of them will be used. The ores (copper, bismuth, tin, kaolinite, etc) will only spawn in certain rock types (eg. Cassiterite/Tin is only found Igneous Intrusive rock) or even in one particular rock (eg. Garnierite/Nickel ONLY spawns in Gabbro rock).</p>
      <p space="10"/><p>In addition, certain rocks perform additional functions. The first anvil you need comes from raw stone, and only from the Igneous Intrusive or Igneous Extrusive rock types, which contain 7 kinds of rock in them in total. The second and probably the most common source of early game frustration, is the flux rocks. Flux is used in the anvil to weld metals together. This is a key progression requirement. Only 4 rocks can be crushed to create flux (Chalk, Dolomite, Limestone and Marble). There is also a mineral that TFC generates (Borax) which can be used as flux, but NOT in TNFC. It's used instead for Boron, sorry. Rocksalt itself is a special rock case, as it is the only source for salt, which can be used to preserve meat.</p>
      <p>The other issue that frequently catches players new to TFC out is the size of these rock biomes (I will refer to areas that a rock spawns at the top layer as a biome for convenience. These are not regular Minecraft or TFC 'biomes', do not appear differently in the F3 Debug overlay but when the world is generated, different rock types are selected for the top, middle and bottom layers. For convenience I will refer to the various rocks generated on the top layer as Rock Biomes). Rock biomes in TFC can be rather massive, it is not uncommon to walk 6000 blocks and see the same top layer rocks and soil for the entire journey. Travel and exploration is a key element to TFC so expect to do extensive walking or boating, but it can be frustrating walking 50-60 thousand blocks to find flux rock needed to progress out of the stone age. Hence this long screed.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>So you need certain rocks, and particularly in the early game you need them at the top layer, as exploiting resources in the deeper layer is far more difficult and a discussion for another tutorial. For this one, we need to decide, what are the rocks we need reasonably adjacent to our spawn in order to have a reasonable chance of progression. This is a matter of opinion and also changes dependent on whether you are playing just TFC itself or within a modpack such as Technodefirmacraft (TNFC) as modpacks will have additional ores and further will utilize more of the ores in TFC that are sometimes of limited import.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Step 2 - Define the requirements -</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>In my opinion, the rocks you need within a reasonable starting area (see note on walking above, for me a reasonable starting area is roughly 5000 chunks of spawn... do the math, it's a big area) are: a flux stone, a stone for the first anvil, a source of the key basic ores (copper, zinc, bismuth, tin, gold, silver, etc). And the key rocks for one off resources, gabbro (garnierite/nickel), marble lapis lazuli (probably more applicable to modpacks), rock salt for food preservation.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>So my basic must-have list is: gabbro for garnierite and kimberlite, marble for flux stone, graphite malachite and lapis, rocksalt for salt, kaolinite and coal ores, granite for tin, gold, silver and cryolite, a Igneous Extrusive rock (Andesite, Basalt, Dacite, Rhyolite) for bismuth, hematite, copper and gold. So that's at least 5 rocks you want within a reasonable area to progress. Again this a matter of opinion and depends on the other mods you're playing. But if you have these 5 rocks then you can get through the tech tree.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Step 3 - A better solution -</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>How to then ensure you have these 5 rock types within a particular minecraft seed? One method of course is to start map after map and either creative mode fly around or some other manual method to check what spawn rock biome and adjacent rock biomes you have available. This is slow and uncertain. A better method is to use Dries007 TFCSeedMaker to generate world candidates to choose from.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>There are two updated version of Dries007 TFCSeedmaker to choose from. I updated the original 1.7.10 version of Seedmaker to the 1.12.2 TFC-NG version <link href="https://github.com/AnodeCathode/TFCSeedMaker/releases/tag/1.0">myself</link>. Dries himself <link href="https://github.com/dries007/TFCSeedMaker/releases/tag/v0.2.0">updated</link> TFCSeedmaker to 1.12.2. I recommend my hacky update because of one key feature. Dries removed the summary file output from his updated Seedmaker. To me, the summary file is the most useful and valuable part of TFCSeedmaker. Also note that he changed the colours used to indicated different rock biomes, so the different graphic files created are not comparable. For this I will be assuming use of my version.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>TFCSeedmaker works stand-alone. It is not a Minecraft mod. It is a java utility that incorporates enough of the TFC world generation logic to create a simulation of the TFC world and then output graphics and a files detailing the world. Download TFCSeedMaker, put it into a new folder alone. Then you need to create a batch/cmd file to actually run the seedmaker and provide it with parameters. While your details may differ, the basic command I use to generate candidates is this:</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>java -jar TFCSeedMaker-0.1.0.jar -m all -r 5000 -n 10</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>This will create 10 map seed candidates, 5000 chunks out (not exactly Minecraft chunks, but I've decided 5000 is within my definition of 'reasonable').</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>So with a command/batch file and the jar, you launch TFCSeedmaker and it will create 10 sub folders, each named for the seed being tested. Depending on the size of the map (the -r 5000 parameter) and the power of your machine, it will take some time for TFCSeedmaker to generate all the candidates. Go have a coffee and watch something on TV. Seedmaker needs all the cores on your computer so leave it alone.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Step 4 - Process the Results -</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Once it completes, you will have 10 folders of candidates. Now you have to decide. My process is as follows, I go into each folder and open the summary file ({seednumber}.json). I look for the 5 key rock types listed above in the "rocksTop" section. I try not to look too closely and precisely where each rock type is, particularly if this is a map seed I'm going to play on myself. More looking at the general layout, and availability of the rock biomes. If I'm setting up a server I might be even more particular and count the total number of rocks in that section. TFC has 22 rocks in total and for a server I might keep looking until I find a seed with all 22 within the scan area.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>My second criteria is world layout. As is clear, travel around to get to the different rock biomes is a key component of TFC. Also, having the 5 critical biomes is rather less useful if all of them are under the ocean. So if a candidate meets the first test, I then check the biomes.png file. This is a layout of the actual biomes in TFC. Actual biomes in TFC are rather useless except that it differentiates between land biomes and ocean biomes. I look for largish landmasses with a good ocean connecting them together. Ocean travel is a much faster and safer way to quickly get to all the various rock biomes.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>For a server, I might go so far as to examine the rock_top.png file and ensure that no critical rock biome is under the ocean. I've even gone so far as to overlay that rock_top.png on the biomes.png in photoshop to get a clear idea of where the land is and where the rocks are.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>How much effort you want to expend on that is up to you. For SSP, having a single Pangea landmass can be convenient if you like. Again I cull out the folders that TFCSeedmaker produces and leave the possible candidates. Then a second pass examining the actual layout of the land. If I'm not entirely satisfied I may run TFCSeedmaker again, generating another 10 candidates for examination. This process continues until I have 3 or 4 candidates that I believe are suitable.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Only now do we fire up our TFC client and actually look at the seeds. This is even more a matter of personal preference. If I know that a seed has the rocks I need, then depending on how particular I'm feeling, I may go further. I may look for nice plains to build on. Good sources of hot water, lava, salt water and fresh water. Pretty mountains. Tree types. I may start all the various seeds with cheats on, enable creative mode and fly about, checking the seed from an esthetic angle. This part is up to you. If I'm selecting for a server I may spend some time on this. If it's for my own SSP play, then I won't do this at all and let the actual layout of terrain be a surprise.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Summary -</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>In the end, selecting a decent seed in TFC is much more important than in vanilla Minecraft. It can be extremely frustrating to be unable to find a critical resource needed to progress. Keep in mind however, that in theory every rock type will eventually spawn, given a large enough world. So if you're really hardcore you can just pick whatever spawn comes up and overcome whatever obstables the RNGejus generates for you and persevere. But if you are just starting out, starting a server for you and others to play on, or just want to know that everything you need will be 'somewhere' nearby. Then I recommend spending some time on finding a decent seed. TFC is hard enough without being able to find flux within 18000 blocks of your spawn.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Hope this helps and look forward to your feedback.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
    </section>

  </chapter>

  <chapter id="changelogs">
    <section>
      <p bold="true">Changelogs</p>
      <link ref="index" color="#CC3333">&lt;- Index</link>
      <p space="10"/>
            <p italics="true">Version 12.2.69 - Bonk on the Head</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Small changes. The AR Vacuum Laser recipe has been changed to not require a Red Crystal. Crystal blocks are in-game but are exceedingly rare (not in this solar system rare). </p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Also, wearing a COMPLETE set of PneumaticCraft armour will render the wearer impervious to falling block damage, explosions, falling anvils/pigvils. I think. I look forward to your feedback.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>firmalife fixes nothing that matters to TNFC. Carry on </p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updates:</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- firmalife</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.70 - Little Bits of This</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Added LittleTiles for all your wacky door building needs. CnB is staying in the pack. Yes, they overlap. No, I do not care. - Thanks to ker(∂n)/im(∂n-1)≅πn(X), n≤dim(X) for his LT crafttweaker script.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Significantly buffed the asteroid configs and enhanced lava output</p>
      <p>- Fixed the AR Log Cutting Machine output for wood ash from logs</p>
      <p>- Fixed PnC Nightvision upgrade</p>
      <p>- Restored the intended Nuclearcraft basic battery recipe (yes, it's supposed to be expensive)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Added a Horsepower Press method for directly making Olive Oil. This utilizes the long neglected jute discs. Thanks to Gaelmare for his work on this.</p>
      <p>    - Jute disc combined with Olive paste makes a Olive Jute Disc. This can be placed in a HP Press to create olive oil. The olive oil can be drained out of the bottom of the press with a liquid hopper. The used jute discs can be pulled out from the press out of the SIDE of the press with a regular hopper.</p>
      <p>     - The IE Industrial squeezer can also be used for a higher yield</p>
      <p>- A pre-configured file for dynamic trees has been added for those that like those trees.</p>
      <p>- Firmalife updated to finally get rennet drops from cows, goats, sheep, zebu, deer... CHEESE!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p>- LittleTiles</p>
      <p>- CreativeCore</p>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- Nuclearcraft</p>
      <p>- firmalife</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.71.2 - Crashing is bad mmmkay?</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Update for firmalife to fix worldgen crashing, and add some new bits</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Update for BwM to fix axle breaking?</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Update for Nuclearcraft, Rockhounding and LittleTiles for various issues</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fix for infinite paper via grinding and crafting the TNFC guidebook</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added recipes for AR Titanium Aluminide and AR Titanium Iridium dusts.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updates:</p>
      <p>- firmalife</p>
      <p>- BetterWithMods</p>
      <p>- Nuclearcraft</p>
      <p>- Rockhounding Core and Chemistry</p>
      <p>- LittleTiles and CreativeCore</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.72 - Well That's Not Right</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Another update to firmalife to hopefully stop the melon crashing fun.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Small config change to make the rock/stick spring regen a little more abundant.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Changed the insulated wire recipes to use rubber rather than hemp cloth</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Changed other Macaw recipes to use Kapok instead of Sequoia in the Kapok recipes</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fixed the Lube Addon for the mining drill eating the hammer when crafted</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- Firmalife</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.73 - Fixes and mixes</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updates to fix stuff.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>TNFCMod - Dead crops should no longer get nuked from farmland in the spring months.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Waterflasks should have it's flask stacking issues resolved</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Firmalife has fixes for milking and cheese wheel breaking</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Let the PnC EntityImport puzzle piece be available again</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Change the littletiles metal press recipes to use a platinum double ingot rather than the bone block (which seems borked)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>CreativeCore updated</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Dynmap updated to release version (Server installs only)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>-  Waterflasks</p>
      <p>- Firmalife</p>
      <p>- CreativeCore</p>
      <p>- Dynmap</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.74 - I Like New Nuggets</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Another fix to the spring regen functions. Any stone/nugget/stick looking to be placed will now ignore grass growing on the block and place it anyway. </p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fixes for little bugs in TFC</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fixes for firmalife. Milking issues and others</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updates:</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- TFC</p>
      <p>- firmalife</p>
      <p>- RH Chemistry</p>
      <p>- CreativeCore</p>
      <p>- LittleTiles</p>
      <p>- AdvancedRocketry</p>
      <p>- RebornCore</p>
      <p>- Foamfix</p>
      <p>- Sledgehammer</p>
      <p>- CustomLoadingScreen</p>
      <p>- Crafttweaker</p>
      <p>- MTLib</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Resource packs (will have to reenable them manually  for updates)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.75.1 - Fix more stuff please</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Update Firmalife to 0.5.0:</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Features:</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Add fruit tree bonsai pots</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Add sprinklers, which water a 5x5 area around the head</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Added a proper water drip particle emitted by spouts and sprinklers</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Add modular climate station:</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Tier 0: the default climate station</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Tier 1: visualization of the greenhouse's protected region, and the location of incorrect blocks</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Tier 2: Planters grow slightly faster</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Tier 3: Enable growing grains in large planters (maize now requires this tier to grow)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Tier 4: Enable growing fruit trees in the new bonsai pots</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Tier 5: Spouts and Sprinklers get watered automatically</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Added some more info to HWYLA</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Scooping pumpkins now gives seeds, 'scooped pumpkin' now unobtainable</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Chunking pumpkins gives 4 pumpkin fruit</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Pumpkin has slightly nerfed food stats</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fixes:</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Pineapples no longer require knives to cut (Fixes #60)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Trellises can be placed on top of each other more predictably (Fixes #61)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Fix planters not giving surplus seeds</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Food coming off of leaf mats should stack more often</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Fix sync issue with hanging planters</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Fix hanging planters growing at inconsistent speeds</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Fix watering cans not watering anything below the player's position</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Making Hawaiian pizza no longer deletes your food stats</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Small change to AdvancedRocketry config. Falling protection in space suit will protect player even in regular/high gravity situations</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Advanced Rocketry got a sizable update to fix a bunch of various broken bits. YMMV</p>
      <p>- Is the nugget spawning fixed? Please!!!! I do believe it finally may be</p>
      <p>- AdvancedTFCTech updated with new stuff</p>
      <p>- Nuclearcraft update</p>
      <p>- Other bits</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- Firmalife</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- AdvancedRocketry</p>
      <p>- AdvancedTFCTech</p>
      <p>- LittleTiles</p>
      <p>- CustomLoadingScreen</p>
      <p>- Nuclearcraft</p>
      <p>- MouseTweaks</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.76 - More Teeth to the Terrain</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>While we wait on the whole regen to be added to TFC *fingers crossed*, here is the update with all the good bits in TNFCmod. Predators will now regenerate in the spring just like crops and rocks.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Advanced TFC Tech updated to 0.2.3</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Number of small PRs from Gaelmare, PyralIron and Shadefang. Adds RH Transposer recipes to cleanup gas/liquid compat. Pumpkin chunk recipes to Horsepower. Various other recipe changes</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- AdvancedTFCTech</p>
      <p>- terrafirmathings</p>
      <p>- Nuclearcraft</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.77.2 - Going  Forward By Going Backward</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>** Hotfix 2 **</p>
      <p>- As we no longer have a Precision Laser Etcher, add the Basic Circuit Board recipe back to the precision assembler</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>**Hotfix**</p>
      <p>Change AR version to a more functional one.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Backing out the Advanced Rocketry update made a few versions ago. It's too broken and no ETA for an update. The other version had some issues but was at least functional. Hope it doesn't break too much on the backout but it's for the best.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Also an update for TFC which fixes some bellows issues and integrates the TNFC regen routines into base TFC. Also fixes the bellows max temp.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>So also an update for the TNFCMod which removes the regen routines. Also changed a number of parameters for metals in light of the bellows fix and the too easy crafting of rather OP alternate metal tools/armours. Enjoy!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fixed Constantan and Electrum block unpacking exploit.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Other little updates. Now that the rockets should work, the ability to dream your way to another planet has been enhanced.... try Hydronalium Blocks instead of Diamond. You're welcome!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- Advanced Rocketry</p>
      <p>- TFC</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- LittleTiles</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.80 - The Door On 1.12.2 Closes</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>It's been awhile, but I was finally enthused enough to update. Get Forge updated, TFC updated and a bunch of other little things. Probably going to be the final update for the 1.12.2 version of TNFC. What does the future hold? Who knows.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updates:</p>
      <p>- Forge</p>
      <p>- TFC</p>
      <p>- AdvancedRocketry</p>
      <p>- AnimalNets</p>
      <p>- AstikorCarts</p>
      <p>- Athenaeum</p>
      <p>- CraftTweaker</p>
      <p>- CreativeCore</p>
      <p>- Dropt</p>
      <p>- DynamicSurroundings</p>
      <p>- EngineersDecor</p>
      <p>- Firmalife</p>
      <p>- JEI</p>
      <p>- LibVulpes</p>
      <p>- LittleTiles</p>
      <p>- Macaw's Mods</p>
      <p>- ModTweaker</p>
      <p>- Rockhounding</p>
      <p>- Signpost (the Borg!)</p>
      <p>- SimplyJetpacks</p>
      <p>- SledgeHammer</p>
      <p>- StuffASockInIt</p>
      <p>- TFC_Decoration</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- ToastControl</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Lots of little final fixes and tweaks. Enjoy. It's been an honour to build this and have it loved by you! Thanks to you all and I'll see you in the updates....</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Anode</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.68 -  It's a rewrite, same as the old write</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updates to Advanced Rocketry and Nuclearcraft for all your newly broken things needs.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>**Nuclearcraft 5.0 update:**</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>NOTE: Fission shield manager connections to the neutron shields will break after this update - be sure to reconnect them!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>+ Added fission reactor decay heat and neutron poisoning</p>
      <p>+ In memory of Paul Ritter, you can now recreate Dyatlov's self-inflicted dilemma</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>+ Added MSR vessel bunch mechanics</p>
      <p>+ Added placement rules for adjacent conductors, neutron irradiators and neutron shields</p>
      <p>* Fixed possible item duplication bug in fission multiblock components</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>+ Added turbine recipe rotor spin-up rate multiplier</p>
      <p>* Completely rewrote dodgy turbine rotor render data packet code</p>
      <p>* Turbine rotors now regain their saved rotation angle on world load</p>
      <p>* Fixed the sound effects of large turbines repeatedly cutting out</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>+ Increased scope of script addons to include Modular Machinery .json files</p>
      <p>* Fixed various technical security flaws in script addon loading such as protection against zip-bombing</p>
      <p>* Attempted to fix occasional bug where script addon unzipping to the temporary installation folder would fail</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>+ Added fission neutron source and neutron shield CT registration methods</p>
      <p>+ Added RTG and battery CT registration methods</p>
      <p>+ Added various helper radiation-related CT methods</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>+ Began introduction of new Patchouli guide book information [thanks to Zanedema!]</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>+ Began introduction of new multiblock OC methods [thanks to igentuman!]</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>+ Added new advancement criterion trigger system [thanks to igentuman!]</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>* Updated Chinese language file [thanks to WuzgXY!]</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>* Fixed chargeable items basically not working at all</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>* Improved quantum computer code output</p>
      <p>* Fixed controlled swap gate decomposition</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>+ Added solidified corium</p>
      <p>+ Added mixing and solidification mechanics to NC fluids</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>+ Added configs for whether reaching max radiation is fatal for players, passive mobs and hostile mobs</p>
      <p>* Fixed rare crash caused by radiation capabilities not existing as expected</p>
      <p>* Elytra can now have radiation resistance</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>* Fixed various feral ghoul rendering glitches</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>+ Added configs to modify machine upgrade max stack sizes</p>
      <p>* Fixed diborane recipe using too little molten boron</p>
      <p>+ Added molten steel in case other mods that add it aren't installed</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>* Fixed GTCE recipe integration conflicting with base GTCE recipes</p>
      <p>* Fixed crash when Gregicality is installed</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>* Fixed glowing mushrooms spreading into the interiors of multiblocks</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>* Fixed fluids in GUIs not being coloured correctly</p>
      <p>* Fixed GUI ghost items not rendering correctly</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>* Fixed custom coolant heaters not being related to coolant heater recipes in JEI</p>
      <p>* Fixed coolant heater recipes with the same input conflicting with each other</p>
      <p>* Fixed some incorrect units on fission component tooltips</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>* Fixed multiblocks sometimes crashing when disassembled</p>
      <p>* Fixed multiblock NBT data sometimes not loading correctly</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Removed many old, unused classes</p>
      <p>- Removed a lot of unnecessary error-catching logic from data packet logic</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>**Advanced Rocketry updates:**</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- This is a complete rewrite of all multi-block machinery structures. Your machines will likely need reforming and/or changing. Some may need some reworking. Recipes changed to accommodate other internal changes. So bugs may/will have crept in.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Also fixed the Modern Lights recipes as the had a number of broken references to non-existent items.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The vanilla flowerpot was unhidden from JEI as it is now rather useful for flowers around beehives.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>-Advanced Rocketry</p>
      <p>-libVulpes</p>
      <p>-Nuclearcraft</p>
      <p>-ImmersiveTech (nothing exciting)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.67 - Beeeeeees and milk and cheese.... oh my</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Firmalife update with all sorts of cheesy goodness</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>TFC updated with fix for bug with false negatives in propick results</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Firmalife updates:</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fixes:</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>    Planters now update immediately when you put stuff in them</p>
      <p>    Mallets can be placed on tool racks</p>
      <p>    Climate Station crashing the game under certain conditions</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Features:</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>    The bumper has learned to speak</p>
      <p>    The bumper gets upset when a player interacts with it while holding another bumper.</p>
      <p>    The bumper will cancel all fall damage from a player landing on it.</p>
      <p>    Added beeswax</p>
      <p>    Added candles</p>
      <p>    Added alternate treated lumber recipe from beeswax</p>
      <p>    Added full cheesemaking system</p>
      <p>    Added wild bee nests (drops useful stuff, but can't be moved)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>TFC Updates:</p>
      <p>  There once was a prospector's pick.</p>
      <p>  False positives were making me sick.</p>
      <p>  Turns out the class Random,</p>
      <p>  Was not really random.</p>
      <p>  Thus we close issue #1736.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>  Also uhh the barrel sealed date is saved when you break it (#1729)</p>
      <p>  Small optimization for powder keg explosions.</p>
      <p>  Tool racks should now be more open-minded about other mod's tools.</p>
      <p>  </p>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.66 - Lost and found</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>OIISA removed again. Bugs continuing to pop-up and it's more annoyance than fun.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added a new mod to provide some colour and drama to the other planets.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added new heavy duty Arc Furnace electrodes, test tubes and graduated cylinders</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Buffed the damage output of the IE Railgun</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Prevent glowing mushrooms from attaching themselves to rocket or space station builds.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Removed:</p>
      <p>- OIISA</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p>- LostCities-TFC</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.65.2 - Something Old, Something New</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>** 2nd Hotfix for Fimalife update **</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>** Firmalife changes: **</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Reduced smoking time</p>
      <p>Fixed vessel wiping when clicked on a device (Fixes #40)</p>
      <p>Fixed planter racetracks</p>
      <p>Added bumper (try to stand on it and see what happens)</p>
      <p>Add beehives and honey</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>** Hotfix for barrels of aged_drinks. Also add Cooling and warming aged drinks (Aged Beer and Aged Rye Whisky)**</p>
      <p>** Restored the aged drinks to vinegar recipe cause why not **</p>
      <p>** Minor change to Silt Excavator vein to very rarely provide Exquisite Gems plus other bits **</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>OIISA is back. Thanks to Clay's swift efforts, OIISA is back for all your burnination needs!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Advanced Rocketry updated with a whole bunch of space station fixes</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Aged Drinks has been borged and changed. All aged booze recipe now require a catalyst. This will prevent barrels of booze from auto-converting to their aged equivalents. Also the output of aged drinks is now 10:1 to inputs. All alternate booze recipes for their aged counterparts have been removed.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>A recipe for slimeblocks has been added.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p>- OIISA (yay!)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- AdvancedRocketry</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- firmalife</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.64.1  -  Jumping Jack Flash update</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>** Update Firmalife with new stuff!! **</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>** Also sadly OIISA had to be removed. As fun and amusing and sometimes useful as it is, it was causing far more issues than it solved. It may return in a different form, but for now it's out **</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Finally sorted out the various steam issues. The cooling tower / heat exchanger can take the exhaust steam from the Immersive Tech steam turbine and the nuclearcraft reactor and turn it back into fresh water (or distilled water if used as input). The various flue gasses used by both Immersive Tech and Rockhounding should also now be the same. So flue gas created in the Immersive Tech gas turbine can be used in RH Power Stations and conversely the flue gas from RH can be used in the Immersive Tech Heat Exchanger to produce steam. Look forward to finding out what loopholes or infinite energy systems I've created with this.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Also the long standing First Aid bug with logging in and being damaged has finally been resolved. I think this sorts out First Aid finally so I look forward to your feedback.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Also fixed up the vanilla chest conversion recipe. It was meant to be only for MoarBoats but as usual, folks began exploiting it. So it's been renamed and it's cost has been appropriately increased.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Firmalife updates:</p>
      <p>New Features:</p>
      <p>- Smoking is back. Place wool yarn over a campfire and cook brined meat or cheese. Make sure you only use logs in the campfire or you'll not get anything out.</p>
      <p>- Added the hanging planter. This goes across the top of your greenhouse (must attach to a wall). Takes pumpkins, melons, and squash.</p>
      <p>- Added berry trellises for your greenhouse. After 30 days it'll grow a berry. If you leave it for 20 more days and place an empty trellis on the block above, it will grow up into the trellis. Then, you can shift-right click it to remove the new bush.</p>
      <p>- Added tofu</p>
      <p>- Added melon slices which you get by smashing melons with a metal mallet</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Tweaks:</p>
      <p>- Changed greenhouse blocks to need a pickaxe (except the door)</p>
      <p>- Added proper face handling for greenhouse blocks, so you can mount lamps and things on them</p>
      <p>- Tweaked placement mechanics of walls and doors again</p>
      <p>- Tweaked dry fruit and trail mix values</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fixes:</p>
      <p>- Fixed major bug with greenhouse detection, check your end walls to make sure they're accurate still</p>
      <p>- Fixed 3-width roof greenhouses not working</p>
      <p>- Fixed destroying planters with a water bucket</p>
      <p>- Fixed Cinnamon trees not growing from saplings</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- Firmalife</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Removed:</p>
      <p>- OIISA</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.63.2 - Metal sounds are metal</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>** Hotfix to add more tips and have them also display on the world loading screens **</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Mostly a firmalife update and some other mods added for performance and my own amusement. </p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Firmalife update:</p>
      <p>OVEN CHANGES:</p>
      <p>- Ovens will now always try to select the cooking slot first for right click actions</p>
      <p>- Oven rows only need one oven to have fuel (the one that is being lit) to be able to cook</p>
      <p>- Ovens will light other ovens horizontally if possible</p>
      <p>- Peels are now only needed within 2 hours after the oven is finished</p>
      <p>- Uncured oven pieces will now drop themselves on break (Fixes #39)</p>
      <p>- Fixed oven walls suffocating the player</p>
      <p>- Most oven recipes now only take 2 hours</p>
      <p>- Peels can be placed on tool racks</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>GREENHOUSE CHANGES:</p>
      <p>- BUCKETS NO LONGER ARE USED FOR PLANTERS. USING ONE WILL DESTROY YOUR PLANTER.</p>
      <p>- Added watering cans for watering planters</p>
      <p>- Changed sound to be metal</p>
      <p>- Greenhouse walls will place up to three high like support beams</p>
      <p>- Adding glass to a greenhouse wall will also attempt to add glass up to two blocks above it</p>
      <p>- Greenhouse walls pop off if not supported by a block</p>
      <p>- Greenhouse doors now place the opposite of where a regular door might place</p>
      <p>- Climate station no longer eats items randomly (Fixes #38)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>MISC CHANGES:</p>
      <p>- Fixed load order crash in some installations</p>
      <p>- Trail mix gives 4 items instead of 2</p>
      <p>- Pecans have incorrect recipe (Fixes #37)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Update:</p>
      <p> - Firmalife</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p> - CustomLoadingScreen - Cause it's been on my todo list forever. Now with helpful hints</p>
      <p>- Modern Lights - Cool looking lights for later game labs/factories</p>
      <p>- ParryWithShield - Deflect projectiles with shield!</p>
      <p>-  FasterLadderClimbing - Look up or down to climb/descend faster</p>
      <p>- SledgeHammer - various fixy bits.</p>
      <p>- Tips - adds custom tips to world loading screens</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.62.1 - Go Nuts</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Another update mostly for firmalife. Lots of wee changes and fixes. Nuts are a better source of food. Trailmix is a thing.  TFC updated to fix issue needed for firmalife.  Also small fix for Halite recipe in Horsepower millstone to drop the proper amount of salt. OIISA update to fix bug with items getting deleted during yeet process. Thanks Clay!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>** Hotfix for OIISA Update **</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Firmalife changes:</p>
      <p>Tweaks:</p>
      <p>- Reworked food registry system internally. Most foods should have their required ore dicts (and some extra!)</p>
      <p>- Nut hammering now has a much shorter refractory period</p>
      <p>- You have to walk a certain distance between hammerings to get nuts</p>
      <p>- Nut hammer is only damaged when successful nut hammering occurs</p>
      <p>- Hammering nuts makes you hungry</p>
      <p>- The cooldown and distance are configurable</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fixes:</p>
      <p>- Fixed fruit poles not dropping from chain break reactions</p>
      <p>- Barley slices uncraftable</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Features:</p>
      <p>- Added pickled eggs that can be preserved in limewater as if it was vinegar</p>
      <p>- Added trail mix, a meal made from salt, nuts, chocolate, dry fruit, and a knife</p>
      <p>- Added barrel recipe to get sugar from beets and hot water</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- Firmalife</p>
      <p>- TFC</p>
      <p>- OIISA</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Script change:</p>
      <p>- Remove sugar from beets barrel recipe as it's now part of firmalife.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.61 - It's a Hard Knock Firmalife</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>** Hotfix to update firmalife **</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fixes:</p>
      <p>- Mallet has wrong localization (Closes #36)</p>
      <p>- Some crops don't provide stats tooltip (Closes #34)</p>
      <p>- Cinnamon trees have inconsistent / non existent spawning</p>
      <p>- Missing oredicts prevented some FirmaLife foods from being put into meals</p>
      <p>- Leaf mat sometimes deleted items (not sure if this is 100% fixed, please check)</p>
      <p>- Drinkable fluids not actually drinkable</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Tweaks:</p>
      <p>- More obvious indications on if your climate station is correct</p>
      <p>- Buffed the food stats of most FirmaLife foods</p>
      <p>- Leaf mats spawn items in world on right click rather than trying to insert into the player's inventory</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Features:</p>
      <p>- Added large planter, see wiki for info. (Yay, sugarcane!)</p>
      <p>- Added pineapple bushes, yarn, fiber, pina coladas, pineapple leather, pineapple chunks, dried pineapple.</p>
      <p>and full CT support</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>First, backed out the changes to storage because of numerous issues and will just live with the other issues that the changes were intended to fix.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Also,  YABBA has been removed!!!! If you still have stuff in Yabba barrels and then updated you're going to have a bad time. </p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added Firmalife. The cooking with TFC mod created by EERussianguy. Adds greenhouses, new trees, new ways of cooking. Things are changed. You'll have to adjust and adapt.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p>- FirmaLife</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Removed:</p>
      <p>- YABBA</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.60 - Blow it real good... optimized edition</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>** Hotfix for TFC issues related to new tooltips **</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>TFC update released to day. Lots of little fixes but one nice one is the powderkeg explosions. Entities dropped by these will now group together and should cause significantly less lag when TNT mining. Enjoy the dwarvish enhancement.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Also added another couple of alternate recipe using booze to have the aged equivalent be allowed.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fixed an issue with nesting of storage objects allowing bypass of size/weight limits. This may have come with unintended side-effects. I look forward to your feedback.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>TFC Changes:</p>
      <p>  Fix farmland turning into racetracks for fallen dirt (Fixes #524)</p>
      <p>  Add tooltip info for small vessels when you hover over them</p>
      <p>  Fix barrel recipe issue where you'd get more than you paid for (Fixes #1692)</p>
      <p>  Remove skeleton jockies (Fixes #1676, Fixes #1713)</p>
      <p>  Players can no longer be overburdened in spectator (Fixes #1723)</p>
      <p>  Added uncrafting recipes for glazed unfired vessels (Fixes #1717)</p>
      <p>  Added loaded check for chunk protection (Fixes #1707)</p>
      <p>  Added gold pan output for previously unused variants (Fixes #1672)</p>
      <p>  Added JEI recipe for hide scraping (Fixes #1704)</p>
      <p>  Introduced optimization algorithm for powder keg drops (98% less entities)</p>
      <p>  Nerfed sluices slightly (this doesn't fix any bug, I just thought it would be funny)</p>

      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.59 - More little fixes</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>TFC updated, so naturally we need a TNFC update too. Not much else to talk about. Updated the Faithful resource pack to the new version as well, so check your resource packs to ensure it's enabled.  AdvancedRocketry updated and may have some fixes related to disconnects when landing on other planets. Also a number of other changes. TFC-Tech updated with some nice QoL fixes. TFC-Decorations updated to fix changes with latest TFC.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>TNFCMod got an update to change the BwM Saw drop from the TFC-Tech Wood Powder (which is gone) to the TFC Wood Ash. So you could also get wood ash for paper making by breaking campfires.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Note: The AT Launcher continues to have issues identified the replaced mods. So you will have to open the instance folder, go into mods and delete the old versions of Advanced Rocketry, TFC and TFC-Tech. Or delete the entire mod folder and reinstall.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>TFC Fixes:</p>
      <p>Powderkegs will produce more consistent drops on explosion</p>
      <p>Added config option for how far away placed items render</p>
      <p>Fixed crash when welding without flux in a stone anvil (Closes #1698)</p>
      <p>Some barrel tweaks including: taking items below 'HUGE' only, better tooltips for sealed barrels, and less data wiping (Closes #1691)</p>
      <p>Updated zh_cn localization</p>
      <p>Experimental tweak to HWYLA and TOP to better indicate what is inside a log pile</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>TFC-Tech update:</p>
      <p>Added config for induction crucible target temperature (#73)</p>
      <p>Added waila integration to the item you are looking at in the fridge (#72)</p>
      <p>Updated hevea recipes, textures and whatnot (#81, #77)</p>
      <p>Changed bowl name to fluid bowl, for clarification (#79)</p>
      <p>Removed Ash powder and sawdust, since TFC has now wood ash (#76)</p>
      <p>Fixed a config parsing issue with latex extractor (#80)</p>
      <p>Fixed CraftTweaker integration with Smeltery (#71)</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- TFC</p>
      <p>- TFC-Tech</p>
      <p>- TFC-Decorations</p>
      <p>-AdvancedRocketry</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version12.2.58 - Get me some Animals</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Update to TFC to fix some stuff. Also updates to Rockhounding and AR for some minor fixes.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>TFC Changes:</p>
      <p>Anvil welding information now outputs to the action bar (above the hotbar) instead of the chat by default. (This is configurable, just like prospecting messages.)</p>
      <p>Added a action bar tooltip when a player tries to open a vessel that is solidified. ("The liquid has solidified.")</p>
      <p>Ingot piles now show their total count in "what the heck is being looked at" mods.</p>
      <p>Fixed #1682: Fix a crash from plucking parrots.</p>
      <p>Fixed #1674: Picking up a flat item with a full inventory no longer deletes the item.</p>
      <p>Fixed #1668: Nerfed bellows to not be an infinite heat source.</p>
      <p>Fixed #1655: Fixed a crash involving addons adding graded, non-metal ores.</p>
      <p>Fixed #1650: Added a missing model property to red steel shields, allowing them to move when you block with them.</p>
      <p>Fixed #1637: Lead and steel lamps are identical.</p>
      <p>Fixed #1629: Small vessels can be dyed in barrels.</p>
      <p>Fixed #1618: Fixed a quirk with horizontal support beam placement, where they could seemingly be placed through other blocks.</p>
      <p>Fixed #1586: Added a tooltip for items that have been partially worked in an Anvil.</p>
      <p>Fixed #1331: Hot crucibles will heat items much faster than cold ones, via the transitive property of thermodynamics or whatnot.</p>
      <p>Fixed #1310 - Improvements to finding old livestock:</p>
      <p>Wild livestock (not familiarized) can now "despawn" if they are old enough.</p>
      <p>Livestock animals can now respawn rarely over time.</p>
      <p>Fixed #1100: Sapling item entities may now plant themselves when they expire.</p>
      <p>Fixed #689: TFC plants can now be potted into flower pots.</p>
      <p>Fixed #556: Barrels now output a comparator signal when sealed.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updates:</p>
      <p>- TFC</p>
      <p>- TFC Decoration</p>
      <p>- CraftTweaker</p>
      <p>- Advanced Rocketry</p>
      <p>- Rockhounding: Chemistry</p>
      <p>- Weirding Gadget</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version12.2.57.1 - Chunks stay loaded. Except when they don't.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>** Hotfix - Forgot to include the better Kimberlite processing in NC Rock Crusher and IE Crusher **</p>
      <p>** Hotfix 2 - Add a zero **</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Mostly a change for servers. Adding the WeirdingGadget mod for your chunk loading needs. Also removed the FTB Utilities Chunk loading by default. Feel free to enable it for your SSP needs, but the configs are managed with servers in mind. Also adjusted the moarBoats chunk loader to roughly match the Weirding Gadget recipe.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Also increased the Sequoia sapling drop rate from Improbable to Unlikely</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Small change to login timeout which may help with some servers.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Adjusted the BwM Anchor recipe to make craftable - Thanks  rhino1998</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p>- WeirdingGadget</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version12.2.56  - Toxic is Toxic, Except When it's Not</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Fixes for RH to prevent crashes with toxic waste. Also all leachates are again pollutants</p>
      <p>- Other updates and patches</p>
      <p>- TFC Update:</p>
      <p>    Minor optimizations to grass spreading logic</p>
      <p>    Fix #1649 - Fixed falling blocks destroying unbreakable blocks</p>
      <p>    Fix #1525 - Axes, hammers and maces now have the ability to disable shields.</p>
      <p>    Fix #1313 - Added HWYLA tooltips for the Quern</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Update:</p>
      <p>- TFC</p>
      <p>- TFThings</p>
      <p>- Immersive Tech</p>
      <p>- RH Chemistry</p>
      <p>- RH Core</p>
      <p>- Crafttweaker</p>
      <p>- Patchouli</p>
      <p>- SimplyJetpacks</p>
      <p>- FTB Utilities</p>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.55 - A New Year.... And Not Much New</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Little changes to fix some niggling issues, as always.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Adjusted the grindstone/millstone plant > dye recipes to sync with TFC</p>
      <p>- Reenabled nether brick blocks/stairs/slabs</p>
      <p>- Hide a lot of the unused TFCTech wires/gears etc</p>
      <p>- Hide the IE Steel tools and armours</p>
      <p>- Recipe to process RH Yellowcake into more usable items</p>
      <p>- Re-enable the Engineer's Decor Small Electrical Furnace</p>
      <p>- Remove all food cooking recipes from the vanilla furnace </p>
      <p>- Setup individual recipes for all Macaw items. </p>
      <p>- Removed the Vanilla Substitution routines. Shaves 2 minutes off client load time!</p>
      <p>- Turn off AR Laser Drill actually drilling blocks and it will just 'poof' the configured ores into existence</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.54 - 2020 Can Go Away Now, kthxbye</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Readded fireworks to see this sorry year out with a bang Readded fireworks to see this sorry year out with a bang.</p>
      <p>Issue with JEI so the recipe doesn't show. Use the vanilla recipe with TFC Diamond bits, TFC gold nuggets to make the Firework Star.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fixed AR Rolling Machine Recipe</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fixed making booze with NC. It shouldn't have quite that much kick. </p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated ImmTech. Added Heat Exchanger. Fixed a number of bugs. Including using ImmTech replacement piping on servers.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Also added the CTM mod to the CF edition.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- ImmTech</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.53.1 - Just Want A Roof, Is That So Hard?</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>**Hotfix for broken brick recipe**</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Folks wanted pretty roofs. So thanks to the hard work of ACGaming, we can add Macaw's Furniture/Doors/Windows/Roofs and Bridges to TNFC. Also addid StuffASockInIt to cut down on some of the pointless log chatter</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p>- mcw-furnitures</p>
      <p>- mcw-doors</p>
      <p>- mcw-bridges</p>
      <p>- mcw-windows</p>
      <p>- StuffASockInIt</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.51 - Moar Boats</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Little bugs and moar boats. MoarBoats brings modular boats. Daisy chain boats together with chests and tanks and batteries.  Dye the boats with a bucket of dye and a modular boat. The boat doesn't show in the recipe for some reason, but it's there.</p>
      <p>To obtain a vanilla chest to place in a boat, use 2 TFC chests to craft 1 vanilla one.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Also:</p>
      <p>- Fix dmg sources. Cold, Lava, Pigvil all been adjusted</p>
      <p>- Fix recipes with Minecraft buttons</p>
      <p>- Fix missing subtitle</p>
      <p>- Stop attempting to load missing coremod</p>
      <p>- Allow cooking of crab and frog legs</p>
      <p>- Make all crates and storage drawers heavy. </p>
      <p>- Configure the Compacting Drawer for usefulness (rock - cobble/ poor ores - scrap)</p>
      <p>- Gating for Storage Drawers adjusted</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p>- Forgelin</p>
      <p>- Moarboats</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.52 - Moar Boats</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Little bugs and moar boats. MoarBoats brings modular boats. Daisy chain boats together with chests and tanks and batteries. </p>
      <p>To obtain a vanilla chest to place in a boat, use 2 TFC chests to craft one.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Also:</p>
      <p>- Fix dmg sources. Cold, Lava, Pigvil all been adjusted</p>
      <p>- Fix recipes with Minecraft buttons</p>
      <p>- Fix missing subtitle</p>
      <p>- Stop attempting to load missing coremod</p>
      <p>- Allow cooking of crab and frog legs</p>
      <p>- Make all crates and storage drawers heavy. </p>
      <p>- Configure the Compacting Drawer for usefulness</p>
      <p>- Gating for Storage Drawers adjusted</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p>- MoarBoats</p>
      <p>- Forgelin</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.51 - Missed That One Too</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Few missing things. </p>
      <p>Tool recipes for Zircaloy and Beryllium-Copper. </p>
      <p>Fix the dust recipe for Zircaloy. </p>
      <p>Little check on the grass growth suppression. </p>
      <p>Change some TFC defaults. (falling blocks don't crush ores or items - so stop whining). </p>
      <p>Changed the scrap recipes on the Metal Press to increase plausibility.</p>
      <p>Cleaned up the Excavator recipes and added more missing bits. Apologies..</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updates:</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- CraftTweaker</p>
      <p>- RandomPatches</p>
      <p>- FoamFix</p>
      <p>- ForgeEndertech</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.50 - Making mountains out of mole hills</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Progress on the First Aid integration. Should be much better integrated with 17% less weirdness.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>TFC Updated! This brings a number of requested PR's including the actual fix for IE Mining Drill crashing servers and the new 'Advanced' ore information display.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>If your smithing skill is at least Expert, you will now see the melting temperature of ores and metals as well as a numeric display of forge/crucible/blast furnace and other temperatures. This is to overcome the limitations of the TFC Temp display when dealing with high temp metals and alloys like Tungsten Steel. This can be turned off in the TNFCMod config if you find it too immersion breaking.  Also can be perma-enabled in TFC config as well.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Crabs and frogs have been added. They spawn on beaches and in swamps respectively. These are Quark Crabs and Frogs so they are cute and a source of food.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Removed the PlayerRevive Mod. It's a nifty idea but it has some annoying issues so for now it's dropped. If I ever resolve them it may return.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Rockhounding updated to fix a couple of issues.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updates:</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- TFC</p>
      <p>- Rockhounding Core</p>
      <p>- Rockhounding Chemistry</p>
      <p>- MineralTracker</p>
      <p>- TFC_Decoration</p>
      <p>- Terrafirmathings</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p>- AutoRegLib</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Removed:</p>
      <p>- PlayerRevive</p>
      <p>- CreativeCore</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.49 - You Can't Have Any Pudding If You Don't Eat Your Meat!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Integrated FirstAid with TFC nutrition. Now your total health from good nutrition affects the amount of hearts each First Aid body part has. Get your nutrition way up, take multiple hits from skellies and shrug them off. Neglect your nutrition and let your HP dwindle? Get one-shot by angry squirrels. Did also make a tiny change to the First Aid config which should give you a slightly better chance of survival.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added some better damage modeling for various dmg sources and made the bandages/plaster cheaper.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added PlayerRevive. Now when you go down, if you've got a buddy nearby, they can revive you. You're going to be in rough shape, but alive and not 9000 blocks away where you last spawned. You'll be beat up, but it could be worse.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The ultimate bucket is back! Okay, nothing really changed, other than I really liked the purple bucket texture. YMMV. </p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fixed the Open Computer recipes requiring vanilla stone buttons.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added ConnectedTextureManager. If you are still using Yabba barrels then you may not want to select this. The barrels will be transparent. Trade in those barrels for storage drawers. Yabba will eventually get dropped!</p>
      <p space="10"/>

      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.48 - Even in the Darkest Moments</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added Storage Drawers. This is part of a transition away from Yabba. Yabba barrels are cool but there is a bug where they are invisible when using ConnectedTextureManager. We'd like to offer/enable CTM in TNFC but the invisible barrels are a little off-putting. So we've added Storage Drawers as a replacement and made them compatible with all TFC wood. There is a trade-in recipe to allow you to swap yabba barrels for their SD equivalent. At some point we may remove Yabba, or just note that if using CTM, they will be invisible.  </p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Surface regen has been updated. Rocks/stick/small ores will now regen in Spring. Also mushrooms will regen in appropriate areas. </p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Other little changes:</p>
      <p>Wrought iron duping in RH squashed. </p>
      <p>IE Jerrycans now consume the wooden buckets. </p>
      <p>The medium animal net is now crafted with Iron Sticks rather than rods. Which means you no longer have to have a metal press in order to construct them. </p>
      <p>NC Manufactory crafting recipe changed a bit.</p>
      <p>NC Manufactory bronze to dust recipe fixed.</p>
      <p>A bunch of NC Alloy Furnace recipes fixed or removed</p>
      <p>More NC Melter recipes fixed</p>
      <p>IE Alloy Furnace recipes fixed to match other alloy recipes.</p>
      <p>Sequoia saplings are now a very rare drop when using Tier VI shears on Sequoia leaves.</p>
      <p>Arc Furnace recipe output should provide TFC ingots for all applicable recipes</p>
      <p>IE Crusher Flux recipes fixed</p>
      <p>IE Excavator recipes refined</p>
      <p>Icons for MineralTracker ores updated for TNFC added ores</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p>- Storage Drawers</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- TFC</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- TerraFirmaThings</p>
      <p>- MineralTracker</p>
      <p>- TFC_Decoration</p>
      <p>- RandomPatches</p>
      <p>- Immersive Technology</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.47 - Eat, drink, be merry</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Adjusted the long broken death penalty to actually function as a death penalty. It will get harder to use death as an easy reset button.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated TFC. Brings a volume reduction in Roosters among other tiny tweaks</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Adjusted Ambiental. Now properly makes Hell hot regardless of what's going on in the overworld</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Add TFC Chromium</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Changed TFC Zircaloy recipe. Was far too simple for such powerful metal. Also adjusted armor stats and temps for making things from it.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added recipes to turn aged drinks into vinegar. For the barrels that you forgot about and don't need the buff juice. Also the aged drinks can be put into wooden buckets. </p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>The ability to use a saw to obtain ice blocks has been modified. It now requires a Tier VI saw. Sea Ice will drop Packed Ice and Fresh water ice will continue to drop regular Ice blocks.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Add the missing diet handling to the ambiental system. Meat and Dairy nutrition will keep you warmer. Fruit and Vegetables will help keep you cooler.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Adjusted FirstAid to give all your body parts a bit more durability. This should help make the mod a little less overwhelming.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- TFC</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- Terrafirmathings</p>

      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.46 - Information is power</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Quick update because a new TFC released. It adds tooltips for saplings and seeds indicating what they require for growing.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Also added the Pakifier. A simple block to quieten the 6am rooster crowing. Just for Pakratt</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Also downgraded Chunk Pregenerator because latest is broken with TFC</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Random new tips added to TNFC manual.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- TFC</p>
      <p>- BiomeTweaker</p>
      <p>- Chunk+Pregenerator</p>
      <p>- Immersive Technology</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p>- WorldUtils (optional for server stuff). READ THE INSTRUCTIONS! It's complicated</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p italics="true">Version 12.2.45 - Oh How I Hate You Chicken Jockeys</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Small update to mostly fix the perennial issue with Cave Chickens. This fix finally prevents them from slowly filling your caves with TFC chickens.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Also added the new birds to the pluckables list </p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Added latex to wooden bucket list</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Fix the NC Alloy Furnace Ferroboron recipe</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Version 12.2.44 - The Dev Giveth and the Dev Taketh Away</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>TFC updated with fixes to sluicing and gold panning. Also brings a new World Generation option to adjust the size of the rock layers. I recommend reducing it to 4 for single player. Lower than that and many ore veins will be cutoff due to the small size of the rock layer areas.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fishing revamp - No more fishing without bait. Too cheaty and silly. Now you MUST you use bait to cast the rod. In exchange, the IE Hemp seeds can now be used as bait.  Fishing is still silly and I will continue to improve on it.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Ambiental changes. The Nether, being literally Hell, is now hotter. The End, is now cold. Also, wearing a full space suit or PnC Pneumatic Armour will make you immune from all temperature effects. Also added the Tungsten Steel armour as a cold protector, equivalent to Blue Steel.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>OIISA added a feature. Don't put on armour that is hot off the anvil. You will not like the result. You have been warned!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added a wrought iron ingot recipe to the RH Metal Alloyer. This also required adding Charcoal Dust to the Material Cabinet.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added an industrial vinegar recipe using the RH Lab Oven. Utilizes a Iridium Catalyst that can be made on the Profiling Bench. The process is a fake version of the IRL Cativa process used IRL to make acetic acid. </p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Small change to the neverending story of chunk regen. I fixed it so that if rockStickRegen is set to 0, crops will continue to regen.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fix the durability on the straw hat. It barely has any.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>IE Heavy Engineering Block recipe fixed. The vanilla recipe is removed and the TNFC recipe now outputs 2 blocks.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Made a number of changes to the oregen. Finally removed some minerals that I suspect never will be used. So Olivine, Petrified Wood and Jet are gone. Also made a number of changes to rarity, density, vein size and finally to base rocks. Most ores/minerals that were spawning in one specific rock (ie: granite) have been expanded to include the rock type (ie: sedimentary). A number of balance changes have been made to ensure that ores are not entirely impossible to find. Check the JEI Vein Info tab for details on the changes.</p>
      <p>Another tweaking update. </p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p>- YNot - allows Open Computers to interface with XNet. Hoping to fix it to support RH gasses in XNet in the future</p>
      <p>- TFCAgedDrinks. Because why not?</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- TFC</p>
      <p>- TFCStorage</p>
      <p>- Terrafirmathings</p>
      <p>- Immersive Technology</p>
      <p>- CraftTweaker</p>
      <p>- OversizedItemInStorageArea</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Version 12.2.43 - Call it a Release</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Just fixing little things</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>- Oredict entry for HSLA Steel</p>
      <p>- Increase effectiveness of Leather Forging Bib</p>
      <p>- Fix recipe for Tough Ingot dusts</p>
      <p>- Minor tweaks to default oregen</p>
      <p>- Reduce power of Terrafirmathings Sling</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Update:</p>
      <p>- Terrafirmathings</p>
      <p>- TNFC_Mod</p>
      <p>- CraftTweaker</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Version 12.2.42-Life, The Universe and Bugfixes</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>A tiny update to sort out a couple of issues with the previous update.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Changed some dust recipes to match new alloys</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Removed some IE Crusher recipes that conflict with new ore crushing recipes</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added new dust recipes for recently added alloys</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fixed oreDict entry for RH dustRosegold</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Minecraft mushrooms will drop TFC porcini mushrooms. Mostly applies to nether</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Grass growing suppression modified to hopefully prevent multiblocks being broken</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>AR Cutting Machine will now process TFC logs. With bonus amount of lumber and sawdust for paper</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Version 12.2.41 - It's a block, and a book, but mostly a block.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Recreated my favourite block. The Online Player Detector, previously a part of Immibis' TubeStuff mod. Wonderful block for turning off machines or recalling drones when you're not online.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Also revamped and expanded the TNFC book. It's got a lot of decent content in there now. Highly recommended.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Adjusted the ratio and ingredients of some of the newer alloys.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added alloys and recipes to Rockhounding Material Cabinet and Alloyer.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Add Filtered Sand recipe to RH Blender</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Renamed the Leather Forging Tunic to the Leather Forging Bib</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Fix the Kebab recipe to handle food expiry dates. No more cheaty kebabs for you!</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Allow fish to survive vacuum. Allows for fish farming on other planets and space stations.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Allow respawn on planets with an atmosphere</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Change chisel and bits print recipes to use dyes instead of minerals</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Added metal press and grinder recipes to automate scrap creation from ores. Thanks eagleeyes005 again for the PR</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Remove the JEI bookmarks from the config</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Add crafting recipe for the revamped TNFC book</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Adjust some IE tool recipes.</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- DynamicSurroundings</p>
      <p>- Immersive Technology</p>
      <p>- Terrafirmathings</p>
      <p space="10"/>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.41 - It's a block.</p>
      <p>Recreated my favourite block. The Online Player Detector, previously a part of Immibis' TubeStuff mod. Wonderful block for turning off machines or recalling drones when you're not online.</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.40 - Don't Lose Your Head, It's just Enchanting.</p>
      <p>Lots of new weirdness.  </p>
      <p>Predators have learned the habit of occasionally ripping a players head clean off.</p>
      <p>Mobs in the deep (Y less than 100) and other places have started dropping new things. </p>
      <p>Add various mob drops for IE Shader Grabbags; redstone; glowstone and soulforged steel nuggets</p>
      <p>All mobs and predators now will rarely drop Arcane Scrolls</p>
      <p>The Infernal Enchanter is now craftable. Barely.</p>
      <p>Soulforged Steel is now somewhat obtainable (other planets are richer in this material) and thus recipe have been added to create stuff from it</p>
      <p>All Bronze Gears can now be used in recipes</p>
      <p>RH Alloyer recipe for bronze now has the correct recipe</p>
      <p>Disabled some COFH enchantments that were unneeded</p>
      <p>Turned off the BwM Enchantment override for mobs. This fixes the enchantment chaos witnessed</p>
      <p>The PnC gasoline (fuel) and Immersive Tech gasoline (gasoline) have been consolidated together. Thanks eagleeyes005 for the PR</p>
      <p>Remove the Immersive  Petroleum reinforced hull as it doesn't work</p>
      <p>Nether mobs now spawn with TFC appropriate weapons and armour</p>
      <p>Added </p>
      <p>- MouseTweaks by popular request.</p>
      <p>Updated</p>
      <p>-TNFCMod</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.39 - Cleanup</p>
      <p>Lots of recipe adjustments to get a lot of late game machines outputing the same types of stuff.</p>
      <p>All the terrafirmathings items using jute fiber in the recipe have equivalent recipe with hemp rope.</p>
      <p>The Arc Furnace recipe generator now uses the OreDictionary name of inputs to increase compatibility</p>
      <p>Radiation shielding added to any clothing or armour increases cold resistance of that piece</p>
      <p>NC Melter had all Metal Blocks removed as they were an exploit</p>
      <p>Grass will slowly die and disappear in spawn protected chunks.</p>
      <p>CnB config changed yet again. Stone chisel is back, Iron chisel durability reset. Raw stone blocks are no longer chiselable as the exploit of chiseling a single bit and breaking it easily was not readily solvable.</p>
      <p>Pig Zombies no longer spawn with vanilla weapons. They also sometimes come with armour.</p>
      <p>TFC Decorations added for some more decorative blocks.</p>
      <p>Main menu reworked and screenshot gallery added. Always looking for more cool screenshots, preferably with shaders. Post in the TNFC Discord screenshots channel</p>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p>- JustEnoughPetroleum</p>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- TerraFirmaThings</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.38 - Same day two updates?</p>
      <p>Well TFC blindsides me with a late TFC update. Has a couple of important fixes so here it comes.</p>
      <p>Update:</p>
      <p>- TFC</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.37 - Can we have Hwyla back please?</p>
      <p>Very minor little update. Apparently the dependency isn't there anymore, so we can return to using Hwyla. This should work much better with everything. Also updated the ChiselNBits recipes/config to allow for TFC log/dirt/gravel chiseling. TerraFirmaThings gem displays now emit redstone signal. See the mods page for details. Also updated the Faithful TFC Resource Pack.</p>
      <p>Updates:</p>
      <p>terrafirmathings</p>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p>Hwyla</p>
      <p>Removed:</p>
      <p>TheOneProbe</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.36 - Cause Gems are Cool</p>
      <p>Terrafirmathings is 1.0 so the update brings pretty new Gem Display Cases. Show off those Exquisites!</p>
      <p>I also, finally, did a few updates to the TNFC book. Still planning to switch over to Patchouli and extend the TFC book but in the meantime I threw some of the tips and tricks unique to TNFC into the book. </p>
      <p>Fixed NC Ammonia and  RH Flue Gas processing</p>
      <p>Extended Old Age length for TFC animals significantly</p>
      <p>Changed the way recipe removals are done. This should result in far fewer 'known good' errors filling the log. Thanks rongmario!</p>
      <p>Blacklisted another PnC puzzle piece as it easily causes server crashes.</p>
      <p>Fix the NC Basic Lithium Battery to use proper plating</p>
      <p>Removed the BwM Shaft from the fuels list. No more converting sticks and getting cheap fuel.</p>
      <p>Updated the crop regen routines in TNFCMod. Chunks updated should now properly unload themselves. I've disabled the rock/stick regen as it needs more work.</p>
      <p>Added AutoWalk for your automated boating needs. Now you can chat and fiddle with inventory while you cross the vast TFC oceans.</p>
      <p>Added ReAuth for those who know what it is and want it.</p>
      <p>Updated the Dynmap renderdata for server installs.</p>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p>- ReAuth</p>
      <p>- Autowalk</p>
      <p>- MixinBootstrap (for Dynamic Surroundings)</p>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>- Terrafirmathings - Gem Display!</p>
      <p>- Immersive Tech</p>
      <p>- Patchouli</p>
      <p>- Dynamic Surroundings</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.35 - Well it's a hat</p>
      <p>- Add a nifty straw hat to keep the heat off your melon in the summer months</p>
      <p>- Remove a bunch of unused/uncraftable items from view</p>
      <p>- Reduce the Gas Turbine startup power requirements</p>
      <p>- Update Waterflasks - Bears drop bladders again. A number of other critters now do too</p>
      <p>	Animals	Butchering		Minimum</p>
      <p> 				Skill			Chance</p>
      <p>	Bears		Novice			50</p>
      <p>	Bovines	Adept			60</p>
      <p>	Equines	Adept			50</p>
      <p>	Camel		Adept			50</p>
      <p>	Sheep		Expert			25</p>
      <p>	Goat		Expert			25</p>
      <p>	Alpaca		Expert			25</p>
      <p>	Llama		Expert			25</p>
      <p>	Deer		Expert			15</p>
      <p>	Gazelle		Expert			15</p>
      <p>- Prevent Firepits from burning up with hot ingots</p>
      <p>- Add barrel recipe to create tallow from raw meats and hot spring water</p>
      <p>- Add barrel recipe to create sugar from beets and hot spring water</p>
      <p>- Add candles and candle holder recipes</p>
      <p>- Update dynamic lights to support candles and thermite torches</p>
      <p>- Cleanup BwM foods. They will eventually get crafting recipes. In the meantime, hide them</p>
      <p>- Add Emojicord as a client side optional. Cause who doesn't what emojis in chat :)</p>
      <p>- Removed the OpenBlocks donation station that was renamed</p>
      <p>- Add JEID cause we're out of ID's captain!</p>
      <p>- Finally add OpenComputers cause we have the ID's to support it</p>
      <p>Updates:</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- Waterflasks</p>
      <p>- Immersive Technology</p>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p>- Emojicord</p>
      <p>- JEID</p>
      <p>- OpenComputers</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.34.1 - Hotfix some bits</p>
      <p>Add ToastControl to get rid of some annoying popups</p>
      <p>Also fix foamfix to allow defaultoptions mod to work again</p>
      <p>Remove error in script name</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.34 - Noname update</p>
      <p>- Fix various recipes with vanilla trapdoors</p>
      <p>- Tone down the debuff on the Leather Tunic</p>
      <p>Update:</p>
      <p>- TFC - Stack those iron rods</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod</p>
      <p>- TerraFirmaThings (rope bridges!)</p>
      <p>- CraftTweaker</p>
      <p>- AdvancedRocketry</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.33 - Fix things</p>
      <p>- Remove Red bucket from PnC etching acid recipe</p>
      <p>- Remove gold dust -> Vanilla Gold Ingot Arc Furnace recipe</p>
      <p>- Remove vanilla dirt from gravestones</p>
      <p>- Remove IE Iron Rods</p>
      <p>- Slow crop/fruit tree growth to match Month length</p>
      <p>- Change PnC Puzzlepiece blacklist :)</p>
      <p>- Remove AR Coal Generator</p>
      <p>- Mobs no longer can spawn with backpacks</p>
      <p>- Minor change to TNFCMod</p>
      <p>-Readded FastWorkbench</p>
      <p>- Update Nuclearcraft; TFC-Storage; Randompatches; AdvancedRocketry</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.32 - Some new stuff</p>
      <p>Think you can make the wind chimes. Maybe?</p>
      <p>ImmersivePosts has been added to reduce the number of people being electrocuted.</p>
      <p>OpenComputers has been added. The recipes are still a work in progress.</p>
      <p>TFC Updated - Black dye stuff works. Crushed Firepits don't crash the world</p>
      <p>Nuclearcraft updated - Rock Crusher doesn't crash the client</p>
      <p>PneumaticCraft etching acid recipe no longer requires Rain Water</p>
      <p>Few more Signpost signs allowed per player (16)</p>
      <p>Other little config changes</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.31 - Always something</p>
      <p>- Mushrooms are edible... barely</p>
      <p>- Beryl now spawns... doh</p>
      <p>- Engineer's workshop recipes shouldn't eat tools</p>
      <p>- Arc Furnace recycling is disabled. Too unbalanced. May re-add by hand later</p>
      <p>- Disabled DynamicSurround sounds in non-applicable dimensions</p>
      <p>- Adjusted old age data and Animalnet config for new TFC animals.</p>
      <p>- Updated TFC-Tech</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.30 - Fixes</p>
      <p>Repair some bad things.</p>
      <p>- Fix the tin plate recipes that resulted in steel grit.</p>
      <p>- Fix making MC Anvil from logs on the Metal Press</p>
      <p>- Fix crash resulting from equipping TFC Quiver</p>
      <p>- Fix MC Chicken spawning resulting in severe server lag</p>
      <p>- Fix broken language entries for Ambiental death messages</p>
      <p>- Fix Leather armour not providing any temperature protection</p>
      <p>- updates for Terrafirmathings, NuclearCraft, CraftTweaker</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.29 - No Free Lunch</p>
      <p>Update to the Leather Forging Tunic. It now comes with a debuff while worn. You will be immune from the forge heat but you always won't be able to move, and your focus will be squarely on your forge and anvil. Also changed the Leather Tunic recipe. Now is made from a Leather Chestplate soaked in Limewater for 8 hours.</p>
      <p>Added a small ore to normal hammer recipe. Now those small ore nuggets can be turned into a normal one at a 5 to 1 rate. Good for those non-meltable ores.</p>
      <p>- Fixed the BwM wicker recipe to use TFC reeds. This allows the creation of BwM elevators.</p>
      <p>- Fixed a minor recipe for Engineers Decor stained blocks to use all the TFC dirt instead of vanilla.</p>
      <p>- Turned the TFC-Ambiental temp display permanently on. Due to the implementation if you want to revert to the default, hold shift to display, behaviour you will have to edit the config/tfcambiental.cfg and set sneakyDetails=true</p>
      <p>- Updated ImmersiveTech</p>
      <p> </p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.28.1 - Hotfix 1</p>
      <p>Update for TFC-Storage - Fixed TOP display on dedicated servers</p>
      <p>Also added the ability to feed apples to horses. Not being able to give a horse an apple is a sacrilege.</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.28 - Creature Comforts</p>
      <p>Lots of little changes to maybe make life a tiny bit more survivable. </p>
      <p>1. Enhancements to the body temperature (TFCAmbiental) mod. A number of changes have been made:</p>
      <p> - Different armour provides different levels of protection. Amazingly, Black Bronze now provides protection from the sun, not the cold! Must be the gold/silver conducting heat to the soil. Yeah, that's it. This protection is also extended to Red Steel armour. All other vanilla TFC armours provide increasing levels of protection from the cold. The TFC Metallum armours only provide the standard protection.</p>
      <p>- A Leather Tunic has been added that when equipped in the Baubles (yes, that's new) chest slot, will protect the wearer from the searing temperatures while working the forge. It provides no other protection.</p>
      <p>- Straw can be used to provide limited cold protection while in inventory. The protection is based on how many slots in inventory are occupied by straw, not the amount in the stack. So spreading out your straw to take all slots will provide quite a bit of cold protection, at the exchange of inventory slots. The exact amount probably needs tweaking, so I look forward to your feedback.</p>
      <p>- Similarly, ice blocks can be used in the same fashion to provide cooling. Ice blocks can be obtained by breaking ice blocks with a saw. Same mechanism as straw, each slot occupied by an ice block will provide cooling. Feedback needed.</p>
      <p>- The Steel Furnace will provide heat while it's burning</p>
      <p>- The IE External Heater, while running and connected to a Steel Furnace will provide significant heat. A lever can be used to enable the heater/furnace even without items in the furnace to process. Looking to add a redstone enabled thermometer which should allow redstone mechanisms to automatically provide a set amount of heat.</p>
      <p>- The IE Electric lanterns provide a small amount of heat when powered. Again, feedback on amount needed.</p>
      <p>2. TFCStorage. Lumintorious has been at it again and brought us another nifty mod, TFCStorage! This provides a number of storage options to increase the lifetime of stored foods. Includes meat hooks, storage jars, storage shelves, grain piles and new mechanisms to combat food decay. Feedback appreciated. The One Probe data on the stored foods is currently broken on dedicated servers, but hopefully will be fixed soon. See the CurseForge page for the TFC-Storage mod for exact details.</p>
      <p>3. The One Probe - We've switched from Hywla to the One Probe. It's been configured to look like Hywla so not a lot should be changed. Reason for the switch is a current hard-coded dependency for TFC-Storage. Makes little difference to me.</p>
      <p>4. Snow shoes may? be fixed.</p>
      <p>5. Fixed the broken trap door and Nickel Silver armour textures. Now you have no reason not to have a Manganese trapdoor. Textures by me, so they are not pretty</p>
      <p>6. The previous changes to allow some of the TFC-Metallum metals to be melted in the forge/induction crucible given sufficient temperature has been reverted. A number of issues arose and for now, was easier to just revert to previous behaviour. A wholesale rework of the metals/alloys/temperatures/armour and tool strengths will be looked at in upcoming versions. I am also going to provide a mechanism to convert the surface nuggets of these metals to scrap for Arc Furnace processing.</p>
      <p>7. Small reduction in the plank output from the BwM Saw and Horsepower Saw. Not quite the doubling of output as previous.</p>
      <p>8. Dynmap render data for dedicated servers has been updated to fix the rendering of TFC Fresh/Salt/Hot water.</p>
      <p>9. Fixed some of the Tin Plate hijinks. The Tin  Plate should now be Metal Pressable and meltable. </p>
      <p>10. The AR Precision Assembler recipes have been altered to utilize Ore Dictionary entries wherever possible.</p>
      <p>11. The NC Light Rad Shielding recipe has been fixed. Eventually want to add the Rad shielding to the Ambiental setup. Will see this in upcoming versions.</p>
      <p>12. Maybe finally fixed the Stone Age boat recipe to actually use all 3 logs it specifies in the recipe.</p>
      <p>13. Nuclearcraft updated.</p>
      <p>As always, I look forward to your feedback and issues. Likely will be a follow-on release fairly soon with an update for some known issues, particularly with TFC-Storage.</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.27 - Plate it up</p>
      <p>- Went through and fixed all the ingot>plate>sheet recipes. Allow plates to be melted. Should hopefully close any dupe loops in plate processing.</p>
      <p>- Fix stone-age boat recipe. I said 3 logs damnit!</p>
      <p>- Allow unfired crucible to be fired in the Steel Furnace</p>
      <p>- Allow some of the other ores to be melted directly (Cobalt, Ardite, Osmium, Zircon) given sufficient temperature</p>
      <p>- Toned down TFCAmbiental. A rework of this is coming soon. More options and flexibility</p>
      <p>- Updated ChunkPreGenerator</p>
      <p>- Removed all the optional for mods key to the pack.</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.26 - Little bugs squashed</p>
      <p>- Add stoneage plaster recipe with items from the land</p>
      <p>- Add recipe for vanilla Crafting Table for Engineers Workshop</p>
      <p>- Fix Engineer Workshop recipes to not eat tools</p>
      <p>- Remove some Steel and Iron Sheet Plate dupe bugs</p>
      <p>- Fix Jetpack recipes and names</p>
      <p>- Fix NuclearCraft Machine Chassis</p>
      <p>- Fix raw fish having zero nutrition</p>
      <p>- Allow grinding/milling of manuals into paper</p>
      <p>- Change manuals to be given out once. Not on respawn</p>
      <p>- Update TFC to Version 161</p>
      <p>- Update randompatches</p>
      <p>- Update ImmersiveTech</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.25 - Fixing the broken unbroken things</p>
      <p>- Changed Chisel and Bits bitsaw to use any decent gems</p>
      <p>- Added all the missing shulker box colour recipes</p>
      <p>- Added a stone age boat. 3 logs and an axe head.</p>
      <p>- Add some quern/millstone/grindstone recipes for boron, fluorite</p>
      <p>- Remove Borax recipes for Grinder and Mill</p>
      <p>- Remove the other borax recipe from IE Crusher</p>
      <p>- Update TFC for various issues including purple donkeys</p>
      <p>- Couple of fixes for nuclearcraft recipes</p>
      <p>- Added:</p>
      <p>   - Terrafirmathings for some cool little bits. Bear traps, Snow shoes.</p>
      <p>   - EngineersDecor for some other cool little blocks and decorations</p>
      <p>- Updated:</p>
      <p>   - Nuclearcraft - New stuff and updates</p>
      <p>   - TFC - Little fixes for new animals, patchouli book, other stuff</p>
      <p>   - TNFCMod - oredict and small changes</p>
      <p>   - JEI</p>
      <p>   - Immersive Technology - Gas Turbines!</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.24 - Break the unbroken things</p>
      <p>NOTE: This Version is a world-breaker!!!!! Do not use this with existing worlds. Due to extensive changes to worldgen, you need a new world. Cannot emphasize this enough!</p>
      <p>This Version brings nuclearcraft and all the bits to go with it. Lots of new ores, lots of new machines, lots of new bugs. We also see the return of Steve's Workshop, now called Engineers Workshop. Nice little crafting table mod.</p>
      <p>AdvancedTFCTech is finally ready to go. This brings an IE Like Auto Loom that is very cool.</p>
      <p>Added a number of small performance mods that may enhance the experience. Or they may bring new bugs. I look forward to your feedback.</p>
      <p>Mod updates:</p>
      <p>  - TFC - Adds a pile of new animals and seasonal colours.</p>
      <p>  - TNFCMod - Adds a number of new ores to bring nuclearcraft to life. Also the mod has been renamed to fix an issue with overwriting bits of the TFC Patchouli book.</p>
      <p>Adds ores/metals:</p>
      <p>FERROBORON</p>
      <p>THORIUM</p>
      <p>LITHIUM</p>
      <p>MANGANESE</p>
      <p>MAGNESIUM</p>
      <p>BERYLLIUM</p>
      <p>BERYLLIUM_COPPER</p>
      <p>ZIRCONIUM</p>
      <p>ZIRCALOY</p>
      <p>HSLA_STEEL</p>
      <p>MAGNESIUM_DIBORIDE</p>
      <p>TOUGH</p>
      <p>URANIUM</p>
      <p>Removes:</p>
      <p>BORON and uses Borax from TFC Itself</p>
      <p>  - SimplyJetpacks</p>
      <p> - Immersive Technology</p>
      <p>  - JEI</p>
      <p>  - Crafttweaker</p>
      <p>New mods:</p>
      <p>  - NuclearCraft (Reborn edition)</p>
      <p>  - EngineersWorkshopReborn</p>
      <p>  - RebornCore</p>
      <p>  - VanillaFix</p>
      <p>  - FastWorkbench</p>
      <p>  - Surge</p>
      <p>  - ClientTweaks</p>
      <p>  - FoamFix</p>
      <p>  - RandomPatches</p>
      <p>Removed Mods:</p>
      <p>TFCSeasonal - Folded into base TFC mod.</p>
      <p>Again, I apologize for the world-breaking nature of this update. If you're curious, the issue is that using this update with existing worlds breaks the metal melting configuration. Nothing will melt in a crucible from an existing world. YOU HAVE BEEN WARNED!!!!!!</p>
      <p>Otherwise, look forward to your feedback. Given the amount of stuff that nuclearcraft adds, I fully expect a large amount of bugs and likely a number of hotfixes to come out.</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.23 - Fix the broken things</p>
      <p>- Crop regen will check if a crop is wild before removing.</p>
      <p>- Add some missing dusts for metals</p>
      <p>- The IE Crusher and BwM Mill failed their Food Hygiene test. They will not be able to grind grains into flour until they pass</p>
      <p>- Fix the missing metal lamp textures and language entries</p>
      <p>- Add thorium from thorianite for future use</p>
      <p>- Fix all the PneumaticCraft upgrade recipes</p>
      <p>- Fix XNet Routing Cable recipe</p>
      <p>- Move the AdvancedRocketry gui items to not overlap with TFCAmbient temperature</p>
      <p>- Stop generating BiomeTweaker output files</p>
      <p>- Allow IE Excavator on AR Planets</p>
      <p>- Fix IE Crusher with Bronze Ingots</p>
      <p>- Wearable backpacks will no longer occupy chest slot. Allowing full armour use while carrying a backpack</p>
      <p>- IE Crusher - Cobble to gravel and gravel to sand recipes</p>
      <p>- IE Arc Furnace - Add sand to glass recipes</p>
      <p>- Fix fish decay times</p>
      <p>- Fix chorus fruit to be a superfood</p>
      <p>- Change thorianite to use loose thorianite ore in worldgen</p>
      <p>- Added: </p>
      <p>     - TFC Seasonal - make things purdier</p>
      <p>-Updated:</p>
      <p>    - TFC Ambiental</p>
      <p>    - Immersive Technology - adds cooling tower</p>
      <p>    - SimplyJetpacks</p>
      <p>    - Controlling</p>
      <p>    - BiomeTweaker</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.22 - Few little things</p>
      <p>- Fix BwM Saw recipes to return lumber rather than planks.</p>
      <p>- Actually implement crop/stick/rock regen. Will regen in the spring/early summer months. Odds of crops regen are 5x the TFC Config regen value. (So 1 in 250 by default). Rocks and sticks and ore nuggets will all regen. If this is laggy or breaking, changing the D:sticksRocksModifier=0.4 to 0 will disable ALL chunk regeneration.</p>
      <p>- Fix the Arc Furnace recipe adding. Stop removing recipes!</p>
      <p>- Added TFCAmbiental - Brings body temperature to TFC. Set the configs fairly forgiving so it should be not too bad. We'll see</p>
      <p>- Updated TFCTech - No more stacking weirdness and easy duping of wires.</p>
      <p>- Updated TFC. Little bug fixes.</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.21 - More things to tweak and fix</p>
      <p>- New TFC update. Adds patchoulli guidebook for TFC. May extend to cover TNFC at some point.</p>
      <p>- Alternate paper making recipes. Sawdust from BwM saws. Woodpulp from sawdust and vinegar in barrel. Press wood pulp to make paper.</p>
      <p> - Add sawdust as secondary output from BwM saws</p>
      <p>- Fix End City loot</p>
      <p>- New icons for items</p>
      <p>- Add woodpulp item</p>
      <p>- Add sheet/double ingot metal press recipes for non-tool metals</p>
      <p>- Tungsten Steel drops to Tier V</p>
      <p>- IP Lava Reservoirs will slowly regenerate</p>
      <p>- TFC Bloomery and Blast for non-TFC metals disabled</p>
      <p>- Lot of changes to planet worldgen. </p>
      <p>- Cargocart exempted from Oversized Item limits</p>
      <p>- Removed armour sounds </p>
      <p>- Removed hammer and ingot recipe for iron plates</p>
      <p>- Updated welding recipes for option smithing skill.</p>
      <p>- Added some ridiculous end game recipe for the End victor</p>
      <p>- Lots of little scripty changes, large and small. Check github if you are really curious.</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.20.3 Beta - Minor tweaks.</p>
      <p>- With all the fun with the missing ores, was time to do something to clean it up. All of the non-surface clue generating ores will now generate a clue. The clue will be a surface rock that does not match the surrounding rock biome. Watch for this!</p>
      <p>- Made another set of adjustments to the IE Excavator. Removed some of the silts and adjusted the setup for some of the newer mineral sets added.</p>
      <p>- Also the rules around metal blocks have been adjusted. They now take two double sheets to make on the anvil. Or 8 ingots on the metal press. This results in 800 units when the block is melted. And also 8 dusts when crushed. </p>
      <p>- Any blocks that do not melt, will continue to require 9 ingots to create and should result in 9 ingots on breaking up.</p>
      <p>- The Oregen for other biomes has also been adjusted to add the new ores.</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.20.2 Beta - The Hotfix Edition part 2. </p>
      <p>MCTImmersiveTechnologies update was yanked and then updated. So we update too.</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.20.1 Beta - The Hotfix Edition</p>
      <p>Maybe generate some Rutile for some titanium? Okay then. Also maybe the excavator could find some too? Good idea!</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.20 Beta - The OMGWTFBBQ Update</p>
      <p>You may/will get warnings upon loading an existing world with the inclusion of BiomeTweakerCore. I've not found any issues with loading anyway, as none of the changes affect TFC worlds. But take a backup first anyway. You've been warned.</p>
      <p>There are lots of little tweaks/fixes/etc in this version. Please look at the commit history for the pack and the mod on Github.</p>
      <p>The resource pack was updated. So if you had it setup before, you'll need to go and re-add it. The defaultoptions will select it upon a new install.</p>
      <p>- Added Advanced Rocketry</p>
      <p>  - Lot of stuff went into adding this one. Lots of config and recipe changes. Please let me know about issues, I know there will be lots. Discord is best place to do that.</p>
      <p>- Added BiomeTweaker/BiomeTweakerCore</p>
      <p>  - To make TFClike biomes on other planets</p>
      <p>- Added RealisticOreVeins</p>
      <p>  - To provide TFC ores in said TFCLike biomes</p>
      <p>Updated TFC Mod:</p>
      <p>     -Changes to mob spawning control. Mobs in non-TFC worlds will now be left alone.</p>
      <p>    - Change mature crops. Mature crops will eventually die regardless of temperature. Immortal crops in tropical areas will eventually die. Currently 2 full crop stages until they die.</p>
      <p>   - Configurable support beam range. No change in TNFC but go nuts if you suck at TFC mining.</p>
      <p>    - Other little bits.</p>
      <p>Updated TNFC_Mod:</p>
      <p>- Add ability to crush whole TFC ore blocks in IE grinder</p>
      <p>- Fix Rich Scrap to Poor Scrap amount</p>
      <p>- Fix IE Metal Press output TFC Hammer with Hoe mold inserted</p>
      <p>- Fix the tfctech copper inductor recipe</p>
      <p>- Updated Time4TFC to support changes in TFC</p>
      <p>- Updated MCTImmersiveTech</p>
      <p>- Updated the TFC Faithful Resource Pack. Should now be recognized as the correct version</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.19 Beta -</p>
      <p>- Fix all the loot tables for some mobs, chests, fishing</p>
      <p>- Only copy nutrition on death if below default</p>
      <p>- Add some logging for a change</p>
      <p>- Create copper inductor recipe with oreDict entries</p>
      <p>- Bump Aluminum melting point to reflect difficulty in processing bauxite</p>
      <p>- Add purdy new icons to main page. Thanks FiringIron!</p>
      <p>- Rope to Hemp and Rope Block to ropes recipes</p>
      <p>- Change JAFF dimension restrictions</p>
      <p>- Fix IE Drill Head recipe (steel exploit via Arc Furnace recycling)</p>
      <p>- Add Treated Planks Barrel Recipe. Thanks Dhs92</p>
      <p>- Restore IE Crusher Sulfur recipe</p>
      <p>- Fix the Hangglider recipe</p>
      <p>- Update DSurround config</p>
      <p>- Turn off Chunk Pregen client UI by default</p>
      <p>- Add IE Arc Furnace Ingot to Alloy recipes (dusts coming soon)</p>
      <p>- Permit Ducks to be captured by AnimalNets</p>
      <p>- Add raw and cooked meats to proper Oredict for salting and use in sandwiches, salads, etc.</p>
      <p>- Remove LootTweaker. We don't need it. Anode learned about LootTables</p>
      <p>- Update:</p>
      <p>   Technodefirmacraft mod - natch</p>
      <p>   ImmersiveTechnology</p>
      <p>- Remove the Arc Furnace Wrought Iron dust > ingot recipe</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.18 Beta -</p>
      <p>- Fix the IE Excavator Output. Was a little wonky. Okay a lot wonky.</p>
      <p>- Enable spawning of Selenite. Oops. It is available from the Excavator too</p>
      <p>- Added a gold block recipe. For future reasons </p>
      <p>- Other little bits.</p>
      <p>-Mod Update:</p>
      <p>     ForgeEnderTech</p>
      <p>     Athenaeum</p>
      <p>      AdHooks</p>
      <p>     TNFCMod - Enable all the quartz things</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.17.1 Beta Hotfix Edition - </p>
      <p>- Actually fix the Arc Furnace recipes for TFC Dusts.</p>
      <p>- Also fix PnC plastic creation</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.17 Beta -</p>
      <p>//Fixes</p>
      <p>- Fixed the Arc Furnace recipes for TFC dusts</p>
      <p>- Added a number of tools to use the TFC Tool Racks</p>
      <p>- Add TFC Lapis to IE Crusher recipes</p>
      <p>- Cleanup IE blueprints</p>
      <p>- Fix the YABBA blank barrel upgrade</p>
      <p>- Fix the coal to diamonds Pneumaticcraft recipe</p>
      <p>- Add Fabric creation recipes to the Horsepower Press (totally legit I swear). Less input efficient but automation is messy. If you want to maximize your usage, go click on a loom</p>
      <p>//Additions</p>
      <p>-Controlling - for all your keybinding needs</p>
      <p>- LootTweaker - I'm going to need this soon</p>
      <p>- animalnet - for all your domestic critter transportation needs</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.16 Beta - </p>
      <p>- Death costs more</p>
      <p>- Nuggets can be made</p>
      <p>- HOP Ingots can be made in blast furnace</p>
      <p>- HOP Blueprint recipe changed</p>
      <p>- Garden cloche usage modified</p>
      <p>- Change recipe using vanilla coal</p>
      <p>- Fix Immersive Petroleum recipes</p>
      <p>- Removed ContentTweaker and BASE library as we're not using it</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.15 Beta-</p>
      <p>Changes - Disabled the old age dying of animals. Without domestic animal respawn, it's cruel and silly.</p>
      <p>Update:</p>
      <p>- TNFCMod - Properly fix the Horsepower Grindstone.</p>
      <p>  - TFC to 153  - Fixes Clean Jute Net cleaning. Other fixes</p>
      <p>- JEI</p>
      <p>- Crafttweaker2</p>
      <p>- CustomNPCs</p>
      <p>- Athenaeum</p>
      <p>- BNBGamingCore</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.14 Beta -</p>
      <p>- Fix Winch Recipe from TFCTech</p>
      <p>- Fix Ladders from sticks recipe</p>
      <p>- Adjust Kaol and Graphite output from BwM Millstone and Horsepower Grindstone</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.13 Beta - </p>
      <p>- Changed the previous change to the Horsepower Grindstone. The TNFC version has been removed. The original Horsepower Grindstone now should work to process all recipes, including foods.</p>
      <p>- Added the Horsepower chopper to more efficiently chop wood into planks.</p>
      <p>- The Horsepower press now works to press Olives directly into Olive Oil water.</p>
      <p>- Adjusted the Olive Oil Water to Olive Oil barrel recipe to allow for processing of full barrels with 40 Jute Nets.</p>
      <p>- Fixed the IE Crusher recipes to output proper items. Capped output to prevent dupe loops.</p>
      <p>- Various other small fixes and changes.</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.12Beta-</p>
      <p> Added TNFC version of Horsepower Grindstone to allow grinding of TFC foods. It is a new block so you will have to replace any existing ones.</p>
      <p>- Sulfur now correctly oregens. Oops.</p>
      <p>- Added ingot>nugget recipes for all TFC metals</p>
      <p>- Tweaked the auto-recipes for IE Crusher to make it worth the build</p>
      <p>- Created source of nether quartz. A crap one and several better ones.</p>
      <p>- Fixed all the food recipes for Millstone and Mill</p>
      <p>- Added furnace recipes for all clay items and foods</p>
      <p>- Fixed some of the food registries - Wolf chops should cook/ Fish should cook faster</p>
      <p>- Broken IE Lantern recipe</p>
      <p>- Fixed slow movement on chiselandbits blocks</p>
      <p>- Updated </p>
      <p>  - OIISA - No more fires in the quenching barrel</p>
      <p>      Mod got fixed so back to don't put hot things in flammable storage devices</p>
      <p>- JEI</p>
      <p>- Guidebook</p>
      <p>- FTBUtilities</p>
      <p>- ImmersiveTechnology</p>
      <p>- TNFC_Mod </p>
      <p> </p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.11Beta-</p>
      <p>- Added FirstAid mod. Adds bandages, plasters and morphine solutions. Also adds a localized dmg model. Seems fun. Feedback wanted.</p>
      <p>- Added Gemmed Redstone Latch</p>
      <p>- Made Waystones actually craftable again.  Through the use of, you guessed it, gemmed redstone latches.</p>
      <p>- Bunch of recipes for Rockhounding Chemistry. All the basic functions should now be sorted for the mod. The basic TFC alloys are also craftable within the mod. Now just need to work on ore doubling/tripling. Soon:  Geminus fluid!</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.10Beta-</p>
      <p>Added HC Steel Dusts</p>
      <p>Added HC Steel Amalgams</p>
      <p>Reworked IE Blast furnace recipes. Arc furnace recipes still need work. As do Alloy Furnace recipes.</p>
      <p>Added dust > alloy recipes.</p>
      <p>Added Wrought Iron Ingot to Oredict IngotIron (not plates) - May have consquences, needs testing.</p>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>FTBLib</p>
      <p>FTBUtilities</p>
      <p>TNFCMod</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.9Beta - </p>
      <p>Fixes:</p>
      <p>Iron ore piles not being craftable - Thx Biletooth</p>
      <p>Furnace recipe not craftable</p>
      <p>Changed:</p>
      <p>Jetpack recipes reworked</p>
      <p>Waystone recipe tweaked</p>
      <p>Signpost config  and recipes tweaked - Thx bobgoogwin123</p>
      <p>Various recipe changes. </p>
      <p>Amadon tablet configurated for TNFC</p>
      <p>Updated:</p>
      <p>TNFCMod</p>
      <p>TFC </p>
      <p>JEI</p>
      <p>Added:</p>
      <p>Debarked mod - Thx Therighthon</p>
      <p>   This mod let's you remove the bark from logs. Either by shift-right clicking a log in the world with an axe, or as a crafting recipe with the log(s) and an axe. Debarked logs are purely for decorative purposes.</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.8Beta -  Small script fixes and TFC Update</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.7Beta - Added a TFC compatible Plow Cart. Now equip it with shovels to make paths, or hoe's to make farmland.</p>
      <p>Added clay block > clay recipe</p>
      <p>Tweaked signposts recipes and config.</p>
      <p>Removed all the borked achievements to cut down on the 8 pages of log-spam at startup.</p>
      <p>Other misc. stuff probably.</p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.6Beta- Little things</p>
      <p>Small changes. Been actually playing through so  had a chance to see a few things and make some changes. The 'big' one is the availability of the wooden fishing pole earlier than iron through the introduction of the copper fishhook. Some other minor changes based on things I'd noticed during my playthrough. Also removed the TFC Debug block from a recipe. Likely nobody noticed but it was in there for testing and forgot to remove it.  Also added a new mod from ClayCorp to manage the TFC Size and Weight in use with modded inventories </p>
      <p bold="true">Version 12.2.5- Beta - Let's Start Some More</p>
      <p>Now with some actual tech mods and 'some' of their progression. More of the Rockhounding stuff is configured.</p>
      <p>Updated ImmersiveTech to ImmersiveTechnology. Thanks for the headsup from Grigoriewich. Now we have working distillers and boilers for stuff.</p>
      <p>Some other config updates.</p>
      <p>Some config  and mod updates.  Added the Orepiles from 1.7.10. A high tier hammer can pound various ore grades into uniform scrap piles for easy processing.</p>
      <p>Added some server stuff: Dynmap and it's renderdata for modblocks</p>
    </section>
  </chapter>
</book>